<add>
<doc>
<field name="id">
VKuPRJyOx3M
</field>
<field name="link">
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VKuPRJyOx3M
</field>
<field name="tags">
Sandbox. James Price Point. Kimberley. Octagon. Perth. Australia. ted talks. Carmen Lawrence. tedx talk. English. ted. ted x. 2012. UWA. Heritage. tedx. TEDxPerth. ted talk. Western Australia. tedx talks
</field>
<field name="categories">
News &amp; Politics
</field>
<field name="description">
After training as a research psychologist at the University of Western Australia and lecturing in a number of Australian universities, Dr Lawrence entered politics in 1986, serving at both State and Federal levels for 21 years. She was at various times W.A Minister for Education and Aboriginal affairs and was the first woman Premier and Treasurer of a State government. She shifted to Federal politics in 1994 when she was elected as the Member for Fremantle and was appointed Minister for Health and Human Services and Minister assisting the Prime Minister on the Status of Women. She has held various portfolios in Opposition, including Indigenous Affairs, Environment, Industry and Innovation and was elected national President of the Labor Party in 2004. She retired from politics in 2007.Dr Lawrence is now Director of the Centre for the Study of Social Change in the School of Psychology at the University of Western Australia and Chair of the Australian Heritage Council.------------------Transcript by Fiona Dean, Feb 2013.CC edit and sync by Joel Miller, April 2013.------------------TEDxPerth 2012 took place on Saturday 8 December 2012 at the Octagon Theatre at the University of Western Australia. Over 500 people attended in person and listeners all over the country enjoyed the day by tuning in to the live broadcast on digital radio.About TEDx, x = independently organised eventIn the spirit of ideas worth spreading, TEDx is a program of local, self-organised events that bring people together to share a TED-like experience. At a TEDx event, TEDTalks video and live speakers combine to spark deep discussion and connection in a small group. These local, self-organised events are branded TEDx, where x = independently organised TED event. The TED Conference provides general guidance for the TEDx program, but individual TEDx events are self-organised.* (*Subject to certain rules and regulations)
</field>
<field name="title">
Why protect the West Kimberley?: Carmen Lawrence at TEDxPerth
</field>
<field name="text">
I want to talk today about valuing the Kimberley, but I want to start first by talking about heritage. It's one of my passions, I'm chair of the Australian Heritage Council, now a great privilege, and from time to time we list places to indicate that they have importance to Australians and in some cases to the whole world. I guess heritage is about what we inherit - the things that have been passed down to us. It's also about the decisions we make about what should be passed on. Sometimes it refers to stories, sometimes to built environment, the natural environment, to our indigenous heritage. It's a very complex story, often multi layered. And people sometimes say to me why should we care about heritage. In an ever changing world it's inevitable that things will get destroyed, places will be changed, languages will be lost. In a sense, it's a losing battle -- the pessimist's view. I say on the other hand, that as human beings we are incapable of surviving without those links to the past, without having a sense of where we come from. Our identity is deeply rooted in our past and its no accident that when you look at societies where there is conflict and where there are deliberate attempts to destroy peoples -- genocide - they also try to destroy the symbols of those people - the language and the culture. And you don't have to think too hard in Australia about what that means to the indigenous people. I want to talk a little about that, beginning in the Kimberley. The West Kimberley was listed in 2011 after a very substantial investigation. It's a unique and precious place. Unfortunately a lot of people don't know it. It's expensive to get there still and they're more likely to fly over it on their way to Bali than they are to go there. I'm not being critical of that. It is an expensive trip and a difficult one for many people to make. And in some way that's been its protection. Despite European settlement and some pretty nasty business when the Europeans first came there, as far as the Aboriginal people were concerned, it's still a fairly intact landscape and a place of culture. But when we looked at it there are a whole set of criteria, a whole lot of listed values that we examined, the Kimberley ticked every box. The geology -- the fossil record there is peerless and still being examined. Unique plant and animal species, in fact every time scientists go there they discover more. The indigenous history is well described but we're still discovering it. European settlement has an interesting character, particularly its multicultural elements. And it is still a place where lore is practiced by the indigenous people, where language is spoken, where traditions are upheld and where the idea of the dreaming is a living thing -- not something of a museum. Some of you, I won't go into these values in great detail, but some of you will be aware that the Devonian reef system there, the ancient geology, the ancient archaeology is still present. A complex greater than the Great Barrier Reef, the Go-go fossil fish you will have heard of, images of ancient landscapes. The dinosaur footprints have become somewhat famous, perhaps somewhat notorious recently. Now well documented in peer reviewed scientific articles - difficult at the time we were making the listing to get all the evidence we needed, but it is now there and people are looking very closely at what is in fact a peerless set of tracks. Some 15 different species of dinosaurs at least - from the largest that ever walked the earth to some of the smallest; giant plant eaters to 3 toed ornithopods. An incredible resource, a treasure for both science and our understanding of our own evolution. That's one of the footprints in the sandstone. Not everyone sees them immediately. They were sometimes described as "unremarkable" and they were able to be disposed of regrettably and "they weren't of museum quality". Well the people who know about dinosaur prints say that they are indeed extraordinary. Just a few images -- the aesthetics of the Kimberley are also truly peerless. Anyone who's been there and has spent time there falls in love with the place and can not understand why we would not treasure such a jewel. Some of you have seen this image of Bell Gorge, I'm sure, or El Questro or a simple Kimberley landscape. The Horizontal Waterfalls, which we are told now, will be protected from mining. That's a relief! The tidal plains and of course the wildlife is truly extraordinary. The water birds, snubfin dolphin, the whales, the whip rays, the sharks, the marine environment is one of the most uncontaminated in the world as judged by scientists who know about such things. The whales themselves have a calving area associated with one of the areas that's supposed to be developed -- James Price Point. And of course the indigenous culture, as I say, is alive and well. You'd be familiar with the Wanjana. We used them as the image for the Games in 2000. For the local people they represent the creation spirits -- not in time past, but time present. We must understand, I think, that indigenous culture does not make the simple distinctions that we do in a linear fashion. And these are renewed by the local people. And of course the guion guion -- subject of much speculation and mystery. We have seen two main dimensions considered for indigenous heritage -- evidence of inhabitance from earlier times. The burial sites, the middens, the rock and cave paintings I've just shown you, the scatter of stones and tools. The places and landscapes that are of significance and we know from the recent state of the environment report that these are truly under threat, particularly the disturbance and destruction of sites. I just want to speak for the rest of my time about a very tragic collision of cultures that is occurring right at the moment. This is an image of Paddy Roe, a man who constructed the Lurujarri Heritage Trail, so that Europeans could begin to understand the nature of the indigenous relationship with land, with culture, with dreaming. I had the great pleasure of meeting him many years ago. Sadly he's now deceased and I apologise if the presentation of his image offends any Aboriginal people in the audience. But his descendants are now trying to keep that alive, that place. It is the place where the creation story, in this case of the Emu Man, actually links up with the dinosaur footprints. What was shown very clearly was that the Aboriginal people incorporated the dinosaur footprints into their dreaming trails. The Emu Man is a lore giver, seen in the stars, seen in the Milky Way. Important to understanding the way people relate to their country, lore, responsibilities, ideas -- about what is important. It was saved once before, the Lurujarri Trail, where there are middens and burial sites of significance to Aboriginal people as well as these stories. Saved once before from mining in 1990. Saved once before upon appeal where we judged that this heritage trail, this song cycle, was so important it should not be destroyed. James Price Point -- with some of the exploration currently going on, right smack bang in the middle of this heritage trail, an important part of living culture. James Price Point - that's a drawing, we haven't seen a model of what's likely to occur -- which will open up the Kimberley to industrial development on a similar scale to the Pilbara, if not larger. I have to ask myself as someone who's lived in this place for a long time, whether we really are going to keep repeating the mistakes of the past, whether we haven't learned, in fact, what's important, what is valuable, what's necessary for our wellbeing. Is it really the case that we should build this place here and as Roe's descendants say "snap the back of the snake"? Should we do this and destroy the whale grounds? Should we do this and destroy forever a peerless and precious place? Because this is not "just a fridge with a pipeline" as someone put it. This is the beginning of a major industrial incursion into what is for us peerless heritage. That's what the gas plant at the Burrup looks like now. That as it happens, sits side-by-side with a very significant indigenous site which has been severely compromised. What we are contemplating is destruction on a scale of heritage in Australia, that we have never seen before. And there are other options. There have been studies that show it will actually be cheaper to go offshore or to pipe the gas down to the Pilbara - some $10billion cheaper, not small change. And we've been promised employment, particularly for Aboriginal people but it wasn't delivered in the Pilbara and I for one am not sure that it will be on this occasion. And in any case we risk destroying a tourism industry in which Aboriginal people are employed in great number. We're also told that it should be undertaken because this will provide economic benefits for the local Aboriginal people -- that they need the money for education and health and other services. As a former politician I say these are their rights as a citizen. As citizens of Australia they shouldn't have to sell off their heritage to break the lore. [Applause] And of course it's driven a wedge through local communities. It's created a great deal of social unrest and there will be more of that in the future. The West Kimberley is not a place for sale. It's not a place that we can trash and I for one don't want to be part of the generation that's responsible for doing that. Thank you. [Applause]
</field>
<field name="lang">
en-GB
</field>

</doc>
<doc>
<field name="id">
tIAofo8GjF8
</field>
<field name="link">
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tIAofo8GjF8
</field>
<field name="tags">
TEDx. Health and Wellness. ted x. TEDxFulbrightDublin. ted talks. tedx talks. tedx talk. ted talk. tedx. ted. Fulbright. CASALA. Health (Industry). Dublin. Ireland. Design. TEDxFulbright. Ageing. Netwell Centre. Dundalk Institute Of Technology (College/University)
</field>
<field name="categories">
Nonprofits &amp; Activism
</field>
<field name="description">
Julie Doyle's talk is called Empowering Healthy Ageing with Good Design. Julie is the lead Human Computer Interaction and User Experience research fellow in applied technology design projects to support active and healthy ageing at CASALA and the Netwell Centre, Dundalk Institute of Technology.About TEDx, x = independently organized eventIn the spirit of ideas worth spreading, TEDx is a program of local, self-organized events that bring people together to share a TED-like experience. At a TEDx event, TEDTalks video and live speakers combine to spark deep discussion and connection in a small group. These local, self-organized events are branded TEDx, where x = independently organized TED event. The TED Conference provides general guidance for the TEDx program, but individual TEDx events are self-organized.* (*Subject to certain rules and regulations)
</field>
<field name="title">
Empowering healthy ageing with good design: Julie Doyle at TEDxFulbrightDublin
</field>
<field name="text">
Meet John. John is a 69 year old man and he is a research participant on one of my projects. And for the past year or so John has been using an application that I have designed to self report on his wellbeing. So things like his sleep, his social interactions, his mood and physical activities and John gets feedback on this in the form of graphs on his self reported wellbeing over time. And he also gets educational advice and feedback to promote healthy behaviours. So around Christmas time of last year John gave me a call. And he said that he had been looking at his graphs and he noticed some changes. He said he hadn't been feeling the best anyway, but his graphs were a little bit 'all over the place' as he put it. And he said that reflecting on this made him realise that something wasn't quite right. So john went to the doctor and unfortunately he was diagnosed with cancer. But when John called me he said it was this sort of self-reporting and, you know, this feedback that he was getting that was heightening his awareness of his wellbeing. And that gave him that push to go see his doctor. So what I'm proposing to you today is that effectively designed technology can support health and wellness self-management at home, even within an older population. So the world's population is ageing. And this is what Ireland's population looked like in the year two thousand. As you can see it's a nicely shaped pyramid and it shows a relatively young population. But let's have a look to see how this graph is going to change by the year 2050. Okay, so already by 2030 we are seeing a lot more middle aged people than younger people. And by 2050 this is increased even more and we are going to have a lot of people who are living to be over the age of 100. And women will still be living longer than men. So, older adults are a diverse group and many enjoy long term good health. But to varying degrees national health and social care systems are preparing for potentially higher incidences of chronic illnesses. so things like diabetes, arthritis, Alzheimer's disease and resulting dependency problems. Obviously there's going to be a cost element. And changing demographics means that there's going to be a shortage of health care workers to look after our ageing population. So as a result, there's been an elevated interest in understanding how we might support independent living. And it's recognised that empowering people to manage their health and wellness at home will reduce health care costs, and improve health outcomes. And there's a large role for innovative technology to support this monitoring of wellbeing in the home. Early detection of problems and timely interventions to address any problems. And this is going to help to support a shift from the current reactive model of health care to a more proactive and preventative approach. And thankfully technology has moved on a lot in recent year. And we don't really need to worry about hardware any more, now we've got the complexity of interacting with technology has been reduced a lot with nice touchscreen responsive interfaces. We do still however need to worry about software design and interface design. Not only have smart phones and tablets become a lot more widely accessible and available in recent years, but they are also embedded with powerful sensors. And this has led to what's called the Quantified Self movement. And Quantified Self applications allow you to self track or monitor your activities or your wellness. They give you some sort of feedback. So types of technologies that you might be familiar with include Fitbit for tracking your activities, MyFitnessPal for tracking calorie expenditure and lots of fitness applications map your run. However there are some problems with these technologies, most notably that they are often designed for younger people by younger people. So, you know, they often look at physical activities or are specific to sports. So they don't really consider older adults as potential end-users. Even though this group of people can potentially benefit from such application more so than younger generations. So we don't really know much about how older adults are going to manage their wellbeing at home. Or what might motivate them to do so. So this is Silé, and Silé is 86 and she live alone, and a couple of years ago she took part in a telehealth trial that we ran to monitor a heart condition and diabetes. And she used this little piece of technology called the HealthBuddy. So during the trial an alarm is triggered for a very high blood pressure reading, dangerously high. And thankfully Silé's readings were being monitored by a clinical triage centre. So the higher reading was picked up, Silé was contacted and asked to give another reading. When this also proved to be very high the case was escalated to a consultant who had to increase Silé's anti-hypertensive medications. So Silé had a positive experience on this trial because technology picked up a problem. And it was , you know, caught in time. Silé probably wasn't going to her doctor that day or that week, so who knows what might have happened. But she also enjoyed using the technology. She said 'I thought I knew a bit about diabetes, but this has enlightened me an awful lot, telling me different things to look for, what can cause your sugars to go high, to go low and I thought I knew it all but I didn't. I'm learnign every day on it.' And these are the types of responses that we are getting from pretty much all of the older people that we work with. They are interested in managing their wellness and it gives them a sense of empowerment. But why then haven't these technologies taken off for this growing part of the population? Well a part of it is due to a number of myths around older adults and technology. And these myths are widely believed by engineers, software developers, designers, even the general public. And the first myth is that older adults are incapable of learning technology. And this is one that I know personally to be not true. I been teaching a group of older adults how to use iPads for the past 2 and half years. And these are some of my students. And yes, the learning curve is a lot steeper, but none of the older adults I've taught have had any problems really learning how to use technology. And more so they want to learn. Another myth is that older adults are uninterested in using technology. So there have been a number of studies conducted that examine of older people to technology. And some report positive attitudes and some report negative attitudes, but many of these studies are quite dated. And the purpose of technology has really changed a lot in recent years. So now we have technologies or applications such as Skype that can connect older adults with their families or friends across long distances. And YouTube is another favourite amongst my students because they get to listen to all their old favourite music and watch classical films and all for free. The third myth is that older adult fear technology. Again this is not true, but older adult might lack confidence in using technology. So for example my iPad students till won't update their iPads without my support just in case something goes wrong. And they are also concerns about, you know, privacy and staying safe online, but sure everybody has these types of concerns nowadays. The final myth is that future generations of older adults will have no problem with using technology because they'll be so familiar wit it. And this myth is based on the fact that, you know, current older adults haven't had much exposure to technology whereas younger generations are growing up with it all around them. What this myth ignores however is that, you know, technology is constantly progressing and changing. And the knowledge required to use technology is also going to change. You know, and, physical impairments related to sensory loss are an obvious effect of ageing. And these impairments, you know, they effect the visual, auditory, motor and tactical capabilities of an older adult. And can further distance them from technology. So you know, this is going to impact on a person's usage and interaction with technology, regardless of their prior experience. So things like, you know, contrast are important for older adults. And guidelines recommend having darker text on a lighter background to help improve visual acuity. So obviously these myth can be problematic, particularly when software designers and developers believe them to be true. So what is true? Well for older adults to use technology there must a perceived benefit. And the technology must be usable. Training and education is really important to improve a person's confidence, particularly when, you know, they are at the initial stage of learning how to use something. So what can we do as designers? Well, we can follow principles that exist out there, so principles around universal design. We can co-design with our end-users. So these are some participants of a project I ran last year where we had teenagers and older adults co-designing intergenerational applications together. So that's right, older adults as designers. They were making their voices heard and making sure that end-application that was designed were not just useful for the teenagers, but also for the them. We need to talk to older adults as end-users. You know, put them at the centre of what we do and keep them involved at every stage of the design process. We need to simplify. Simplify the language that's used and avoid jargon. Avoid using symbols and icons that might not be easily understood or interpreted. And you know, don't have too many functions or features. Think about what's really necessary. And we should design interfaces that look nice. Avoid information overload and where feedback is provided in the case of wellness applications make sure that feedback is easily understood, easily interpreted and supports awareness. Finally we need to motivate, So you know, the purpose of health and wellness applications is to support healthy wellbeing so people need to be encouraged to use them long term. And you know, we can do this by keeping content engaging and fresh and useful, but designers also need to understand theories of motivation and theories of behaviour change. And integrate these into the designs. So back to John. When I was evaluating his experience of the application with him, he said 'it was good to see the graph, you know. And some days you were way down, but you'd say to yourself after seeing it. It's time I bucked myself up here. So you'd find you were moping about less. It was like a little prompter.' So awareness of changes in wellbeing is key to successful ageing. And you know, it can empower a person to alter their behaviour or to do something about the changes that have been noticed. And I've spoken about how well designed technology can support this. But it's important to remember that technology should only ever act as an enabler to healthy ageing, rather than a replacement for current practice and services. Thank you.
</field>
<field name="lang">
en-GB
</field>

</doc>
<doc>
<field name="id">
fjdo34fax8k
</field>
<field name="link">
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fjdo34fax8k
</field>
<field name="tags">
ted x. music. TEDxDamlaan. tedx talks. tedx talk. ted talks. ted talk. TEDx. art. tedx. ted. community power
</field>
<field name="categories">
Nonprofits &amp; Activism
</field>
<field name="description">
Don't avoid a problem, create it", says Ronald Ligtenberg. And he knows. By making the impossible possible he transfers his passion for music into parties for deaf people. All over the world. Come on and smell, taste, move  with the man who invented 'possibilizing'.In the spirit of ideas worth spreading, TEDx is a program of local, self-organized events that bring people together to share a TED-like experience. At a TEDx event, TEDTalks video and live speakers combine to spark deep discussion and connection in a small group. These local, self-organized events are branded TEDx, where x = independently organized TED event. The TED Conference provides general guidance for the TEDx program, but individual TEDx events are self-organized.* (*Subject to certain rules and regulations
</field>
<field name="title">
The art of possibilizing: Ronald Ligtenberg at TEDxDamlaan
</field>
<field name="text">
Ladies and gentleman The point I would like to make today is if you want to develop something create a problem if you look at it,  our whole society is built around avoiding problems if you look at our educational system is about preventing failures instead of dealing with failures I would like to take you on a journey in which I develop myself and many other things by creating a problem that did not exist before I would like to take you back to 2002 when my life was about two things. One was music I was DJ I was working at a music venue I had my own radio show. I love music and the other thing in my life it was important to be as cool as possible I gotta tell you I was pretty good at that had a cool car, cool job cool friends. I even had a cool dog. And my sister said at some point to me Ronald your life is really cool right? she said yeah but it's actually so cool, that it's ice cold. and I didn't like to hear that but I knew she had a point until then my longest romantic relationship that lasts for no longer than five months i ran away the time she said if you really go for it if you take a stand for something you can achieve way more than you think I got curious. We had conversations, read books. followed some courses and I realize that this whole coolness was basically just a mask to not face my own fear of failure and we got on and she said if you take on something that you really take a stand for you can make the impossible possible. For somebody who's trying to be cool that's quite a boring statement but again I got curious. She said if you take something out of your comfort zone you get to face your own believes in your own talent of your own potential and I started thinking okay she said you can make the impossible possible what in my world of music is impossible and I thought about deaf people if I could get deaf people go nuts about music that's pretty impossible at same time I got this feeling in my stomach like: this is great I should do this. so I shared it with some friends in my environment and they all said: music event for deaf people? that's so bizarre let's do it! but I didn't know any deaf people I thought they were living in one big house in the middle of the country and I looked on the internet and send out some emails and the first reaction I got back was who are you to help us, we're not waiting for the next hearing person who thinks what's right for us we have our own events we have our own parties thank you. And I was like... until then nobody ever accuse me from helping somebody else I was way too cool for that but I was also curious where his reactions reaction was coming from and then I had lesson number one deaf people as well as many other disabled people are quite fed up with hearing Persons who think: hey let's help them. because you almost automatically put them in a victim role and they don't consider themselves as victims Aimee Mullins ones had this amazing TED talk in which she said the biggest limitation disabled people have is the fact that we call them disabled people When I mailed back to this guy and said: listen don't worry I don't want to help you I just wanna organize a great event. I want to develop something and you might as well help me maybe and they said okay great event we're interested in that as well so we set together and we started looking at what they could do well they cannot hear but they could smell the could taste they could see and they could touch and if you look at music, music is basically an emotion emotion translated into sounds and noises so we thought okay most deaf people cannot get the melody of the music but they can get the emotion we just need to stimulate the other senses based on that emotion And with smell and sense you can evoke emotions i can speak about that for hours but I rather practice what I preach so I would like to experience something and what you'll see is a video how it will work you will smell ginger to spice it up a bit you will hear the noises you also will get a powerful passion fruit pie with a ginger chilli and some exploding sugar and you got comfortable seats which in you probably will be blown away Tonight we have Sencity in Paradiso, which is very special for us as it is one of the most know pop music venues in the Netherlands very beautiful building very intimate lots of ambiance, will have a very special line-up, good musicians Aroma Jockey that will spread senses. We'll have a food jockey that has foodsensation the vibrating dance floor, signdancers who translate the lyrics in singnlanguage on stage video jockeys and text jockeys who works on the subtitling and the love little small things that all tickle and stimulate all senses gonna be a blast tonight! the essence of this event was that we made something impossible possible or as we call it: possibilizing Possibilizing for us is to think and act and in possibilities and there's really no situation how bad or sad whatever circumstance you can not think for something that is possible our first event was in 2003 so after that succeded we had to think of a new impossibility to possibelize which would then be to bring the concept all over the world we've been all over Europe and in London and Berlin and Madrid in Brussels Finland we've also been in Miami, Jamaica, Mexico, we've been in Brazil in Sao Paulo Johannesburg, Cape Town, Sydney Auckland only Asia I still coming up so if anyone of you is interested in taking that on. Please let me know And a other thing that we like to take on is to make events more accessible for disabled people but then in such a way that the regular audience can enjoy as wel for example a wheelchair toilet that's such an art piece that events want to book just that art piece and then by accident make the event accessible as well But to round it up I'm not the same person anymore I can still be cool every now and then but there is more possible in life for me as well what I like to say mostly is that whenever you face a problem, an obstacle, limitation restriction whatever booring word you give to it. don't run away because it might just be jumping board that can change your life or the life of many other people thank you
</field>
<field name="lang">
en-GB
</field>

</doc>
</add>
