<add>
<doc>
<field name="id">
B-pZ-BO9MUc
</field>
<field name="link">
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=B-pZ-BO9MUc
</field>
<field name="tags">
ted. Guatemala. reading. ted talks. kindle. books. tedx talk. ereader. libraries. ted talk. ted x. educational. education. UFM. tedx talks. digital. literature. learning. TEDx. TEDxUFM. novel. library. tedx
</field>
<field name="categories">
Education
</field>
<field name="description">
Grete Pasch is an expert in metadata design, academic libraries, computer systems implementation, digitization projects, rich media production, digital library management, e-learning, and higher education. She is currently vice dean of the Central Library at Effat University in Saudi Arabia. Previously, she was director of Academic Information Resources and the Ludwig von Mises Library at Universidad Francisco Marroqu\xedn in Guatemala.She also founded and directed UFM's New Media department. Pasch was director of the Learning Resource Center of The Scholar Ship and information technology consultant at the Texas State Library &amp; Archives (TSLAC).In the spirit of ideas worth spreading, TEDx is a program of local, self-organized events that bring people together to share a TED-like experience. At a TEDx event, TEDTalks video and live speakers combine to spark deep discussion and connection in a small group. These local, self-organized events are branded TEDx, where x = independently organized TED event. The TED Conference provides general guidance for the TEDx program, but individual TEDx events are self-organized.* (*Subject to certain rules and regulations)
</field>
<field name="title">
TEDxUFM: Grete Pasch - I can give you books
</field>
<field name="text">
Thank you. This the first page of the first book that I ever read by myself. I was a student at the German School of Guatemala, here in Guatemala City. And, I had just received a conical cardboard container just like these --it's a tradition at German schools--, and inside I found a new box of lead pencils, a sharpener, an eraser, some notebooks, and, of course, my book: this book. Let me show it to you: my first book, which I've kept all these years.  So, I loved my book, it smelled nice, it was mine, it was clean, it was new, it was wow!  I loved it.  And, very soon we went from reading single names, as in the first page: to this, and then to this, which is a story.  I don't know how we got there so fast but I was fascinated. The pictures, which I should've understood were actually explained by the words, and it was magical.  It was amazing. I loved it.  From there, we moved on to the second book, which probably a lot of you used: this one, maybe familiar to some of you: Pepe y Polita. So, this book had more stories, and dialogues, and more text, and some pictures; and I know that by September, twenty-second of September, I was able to read this.  So, I was very happy, and I was very glad that I had moved so fast so far.  I was hooked with reading. Then, they organized, the teachers of the school, organized a reading contest, and we all had to read aloud passages from several books. The winners of this contest were taken to a room where there was a big table, and on the table they had piled up books. And, they told us: "as a winner, you have the privilege of picking any book you like and it will be yours." And, I picked this book of prehistoric beasts, which I still have, of course.  It had a different smell from my previous book, but I loved it, and I can remember the smell, too, so... Many of you may be familiar with this set, too.  My family was great.  They gave me books, they encouraged my reading, and this is a set that had a little bit of everything. It's my first encyclopedia, written for children.  It had everything: science, technology, even magic tricks. And my favorite of the set was this one. It talked about submarines and ships, and the Panama Canal.  I was fascinated. I didn't understand maybe what it had meant to build the Panama Canal, but I was impressed that people were working so long, so hard, to do this.  So, this was an important book for me.  Unfortunately, I don't have it any more, but that's another story. So, my family, they were giving me access to their books; maybe, fifteen hundred books in all: my grandparents', my uncle's, my aunt's, and my father would also buy books for me. I remember reading this book and discussing it with my uncle.  It was a lot of fun to do that.  I loved it. And, then, a few weeks ago, when I was thinking about this talk, I was thinking about why my family was encouraging me so much giving me all these books; and I, just by coincidence I was wondering about that, and I turned on the TV and there was this movie on: The Princess Diaries. I don't know if any of you have watched it, but the basic argument is that Julie Andrews plays the queen of a little European country, and she's looking for her lost granddaughter who has to take over the throne.  So, her granddaughter till now has been living in the US, and she doesn't know she's a princess at all. So, Julie Andrews tells her: "You are the princess of Genovia."  And, the girl says: "Me, a princess? But I've never led anybody.  How can I do that?"  And, Julie says: "We'll accept the challenge of helping you become the princess that you are.  Oh, I can give you books.  You will study languages, history, art, political science." Notice she didn't say "you will read children's encyclopedia" or "you will read novels for fun."  Serious stuff. What's the reaction of the girl?  Hum.  Not really convinced. But what I found with reading was that some of these books were really hard but I liked the challenge. And, I had to because my family was asking me: Did you read it?  My grandfather would said: Did you read the book I loaned to you?  And, there was some discussion and help. My mother, on the other hand, she was the practical person in the family.  Here, she is when she was, I don't know, three,  four years old, with her little unicycle.  And, she would tell me: Books?  Go. Take your bicycle, go outside,  live in the real world.  Don't get stuck with books. You can read them later when you're older.  But now enjoy life. And, you know, at the time this shocked me, but the more I think about it, the more I realize there's something important there.  So, I've always kept that in mind. So, in high school we read more serious books, maybe.  Lord of the Flies made a deep impression on me. But, this is the book that I mostly remember from my high-school years.  It's a novel, German novel, from the post-war era.  And, it's very dark and sad. It talks about six characters living in an oppressed village and they're trying to run away from there. But, at the center of the story is this little statue of a monk.  Now, look at the monk, the way he's reading his book. He's totally immersed in the book.  You can see that he's focusing on it.  He's trying to understand it, but at the same time, there's a certain tension in him.  You can see that maybe he's not just absorbing; he's thinking about it. And, he's trying to decide by himself if this is something he wants to believe or not.  So, this is the actual character, that's at the center of the novel, and the characters in the novel try to save this one.  So, at that time I was like: "Why do we have to read this dark novel?  And, I don't really understand what's the point of this."  But, our professor, thank God, he was encouraging, and he was making us think. This is a very important concept.  And, I've been spending all my life, I think, trying to follow up on this, trying to think by myself to make my own mind about the books I read.  So, I came to UFM and I studied Engineering, maybe a ten-thousand book library, but it had all the books that I needed for computer science, for... really understanding what this discipline was all about. But then, when I left for grad school, and I went to the huge libraries --we're not talking a few thousand or ten-thousands of books; we're talking millions of books, millions.  What do you do there?  Well, you browse, and you are happy, and if you like books, this is amazing to be there. But, of course, I also knew that in Guatemala, we would probably never have a library like this. Ten million volumes that easily cost a hundred million dollars, it's never gonna happen in Guatemala. That's what I thought at that time.  And, also, the bookstores. When I left Guatemala and I went abroad and I saw all the bookstores, and I started buying books: used, new, and sending them home; we finally posted this little note in my study: "Home is where you keep your stuff while you're out there getting more stuff and sending it home". So, very soon I had all these books that I had stored here at my mother's house. In the end, I decided to go full way and study Librarianship, and I ended up managing the Learn Resource Center on this ship, it's called The ScholarShip.  This was a traveling university, and we went around the world, and of course any university needs a library. And, the first thing to build a library is to have shelves. So, let me tell you how you run a library, in about three minutes.  You have shelves and you need books; so, there was a consulting librarian; she ordered the books and she had them delivered to the ship.  So, that's a function that's called selection and acquisition. Now, we have the books.  We have to put them on the shelf.  Well, they have to go on the shelf in a certain order. And, if you've ever gone to a library, and wrote down the number of the book and then looked for it on the shelf, you should know that that number is actually quite magical.  It's a code for a portion of the universe of knowledge. So, here are the books.  Here's the stamp, very important, you have to stamp your books, so that if somebody takes it, you will know where it's from. You don't just stamp it once.  At least twice or maybe in three different places.  Then, you record the book in your lists: you make an inventory.  And, so, we had a manual inventory but we also entered it into the computer; and you put the right number on the spine, so the book goes on the right place on the shelf. So, that's what we were doing there.  And, of course, this is a ship, it moves, so the shelves had this protective device, so the books wouldn't fall over, all over  the place.  So, now the library is ready for use and students come, they  use it. We were at sea for sometimes seven days, ten days at a time. And the books were used a lot.  Our Internet connection was really slow.  Facebook was just getting started, but you couldn't really even use Facebook.  It was so slow and expensive to use.  So, the books were a good alternative. We also had downloaded Wikipedia, so the students had access to some reference sources. Of course, it was not enough to research but it was something.  And, the books got checked out, so we were circulating the books, and people would use them for like identifying birds they saw, and then they would bring them back. Sometimes, the books can come back wet or damaged, and then we had to replace them: reorder them.  And all of that has a big cost. So, here is the check-in; students worked in the library, and we would re-shelve them; and that was the library. Now, notice it was a ship, and we did go through the Panama Canal, and at that time I was hoping, I was wishing I could have this book again with me just to compare if what I had read so many years before was even close to the truth. We went through the Corte Culebra, which I couldn't understand when I read it in the book, but then when I saw it, it was amazing; and of course, the "locks," quite an amazing experience. But everything good comes to an end, they say.  Unfortunately, the program ended after the first year; and we had to pack up the library. But this gives you a nice life-cycle for a library.  We packed it up in boxes and it was shipped off to Ghana, where it became part of the University of Ghana's collection. So, empty, empty shelves.  That's what waited me at home.  My mother had packed... well, I had to help her packed all my books and we had to get rid of many of them.  It was hard. I kept some, the ones that I considered important, special for me.  But many I just gave away. I didn't have any more space for my growing collection of books. Librarians do the same thing, it's called weeding, you know, like you pull the weeds in a field. We are weeding all the time in libraries, we get rid of the books that nobody is reading, or that nobody wants, or that are completely out of date, like this Dbase programming book. Shelving space is a big issue for libraries, and mass storage has been one of the solutions.  So, you still keep the books, you don't give them away.  But if your library has two million books that nobody has used in the last 15 years, which can happen easily, then, you put them in storage. University of Chicago came up with a great solution: they put them in storage under their campus; so that, you can get instant access to the books, but you have a beautiful reading room on top of that big underground storage. This is the underground storage where the books are.  And it takes 20 minutes to retrieve them. Another solution is digitization, and this is one of the books that was digitized by Universidad [Francisco] Marroquín. It's very convenient, you digitize a book, you place it online, you don't have to ship it to keep it on the shelves, and everybody can have access to it. Of course, if you want to get a book these days, you can always get the physical book, but you can also get a digital version. And, if you looked above the yellow button, it says "Rent with one click."  You can now rent books from Amazon; so, you don't even have to keep the digital copy forever.  It will disappear.  It will die. You can even lend books online; so, if you purchased some books, you can lend them or find books that you can lend. But, if you're really nostalgic, you can even get online and buy that copy of The Count of Monte Cristo again in the original form, you know, the same edition; if you look for stuff, you will find it eventually, but who wants to bother with physical things? Look for the free legal copy that is available online in all the different formats that you may want.  So, books are digital. What's the future of libraries and bookstores?  This is a picture I took at the Newark, Airport in 2007. Borders and this announcement on the wall, right?  The new Sony Reader coming your way, and Borders going about its business, selling books, like always. All of these books are now available digitally, and Borders has closed.  This is a picture I took last week in the Houston Airport. Borders bookstores have disappeared.  Will the same happen to libraries?  I'm sure.  Libraries are sustained by their clients, and if you look at this, this is the circulation, the times and the number of books that have been checked out in average per person, per year in the US since the 1850. And, it has a tendency to go down.  It's gone down from 20 to about 6, last year.  Same thing is happening in academic libraries: from about 26 per person, maybe 15 years ago, to less than... about 15.  So, there's a strong trend.  People are not really using libraries that much. They're not checking out books that much.  They may be using libraries for other things but not to get the books. And, this is very clear in science and technology libraries like this one.  Science and technology libraries are getting rid of their books. Stanford University, they got rid of seventy thousand books; they left only ten thousand on the shelves.  And, this is the library where I work now, at Effat University, it's an engineering college and we're building... yeah, I have to also learn how to read this, a little bit. We are now designing a new library, and it will have a museum, that's a round shape, and it will have lots of reading space, but very little space for shelves if you compare it to what libraries used to be like. So, if librarians are maybe going to lose their jobs because all these libraries are going to be closing, what are they going to be doing? This is a quote that my husband loves, it's from Ralph Waldo Emerson.  And, he says we should have professors of books. Well, maybe we should, maybe librarians can become professors of books and guide us in finding worthwhile readings. Maybe librarians can go step further and teach us through the books, like this ... interesting idea that Stephenson has in this novel, highly recommended, I have a copy here if anybody wants to loan it, to take it. But what becomes of our shelves if we get rid of books?  They become empty. They disappear, they no longer talk about us, they don't tell us "who you are" by the books, the company they keep. Or maybe, they will, but we will display it in a different way, with different kinds of devices or lists online. But, for me what's important is no matter what format the books take.  If you look at this image, remember the monk reading the book? Well, there she is reading a book on a kindle.  And I hope she's engaging all her imagination, her intelligence, her power of decision to believe or not what's in the book, and to make the most... the best use of it that she can. And I also have a parting thought and it is this: Doesn't this picture make you feel like you wish you could give her books or e-books? Thank you.
</field>
<field name="lang">
en-US
</field>

</doc>
<doc>
<field name="id">
sJq00wVK4RI
</field>
<field name="link">
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sJq00wVK4RI
</field>
<field name="tags">
ted. unicamp. tedxunicamp. tedx talk. ted talks. ted talk. ted x. tedx. city2. tedx talks
</field>
<field name="categories">
Nonprofits &amp; Activism
</field>
<field name="description">
In the spirit of ideas worth spreading, TEDx is a program of local, self-organized events that bring people together to share a TED-like experience. At a TEDx event, TEDTalks video and live speakers combine to spark deep discussion and connection in a small group. These local, self-organized events are branded TEDx, where x = independently organized TED event. The TED Conference provides general guidance for the TEDx program, but individual TEDx events are self-organized.* (*Subject to certain rules and regulations)I
</field>
<field name="title">
Equil\xedbrio s\xf4nico e meio ambiente: Jairo Silverira at TEDXUnicamp City 2.0
</field>
<field name="text">
Good morning everyone I'm here to do an account of an experience with students from elementary school from 7 to 10 years old experience a pedagogical action within school music education and trying to work with students experience of a language developing a language Art as a discussion of interdisciplinary nature There were two experiments involving people's relationship with the sonic environment and the relationship between people and their quality of life with respect to the ambient they are immersed being it among the city the field or the forest the first experiment is a musical composition entitled Echoes of the Forest a suite in four movements for orchestra of paper This project had its beginning on World Water Day where it was proposed to the children to question the intelligent Water consumption from there we were manipulating the and paper. We thought it would be interesting To make a warning about the excessive consumption of water and this alert should be made in an artistic fashion by creating the elaboration of a work of art made of paper, its manipulation and transforming it in musical instruments Therefore we were trying to create a relationship between students with the role , with the message we wanted to pass, in a musical presentation this work the orchestra paper besides involving the discussion ecological it also involved the practice to bring to the classroom new ideas and new concepts aesthetic a new composition which is but not always performed is shown an aesthetic compositional contemporary then these children to manipulate paper were discovering them real musical instruments and it is from these instruments Musical managed transform this management role in language and then pass a language as idea, spend a reflection try to reflect on these ecological issues we relied a lot on ... concept of acoustic ecology and this concept is so this interdisciplinary relationship music, but also an ecological relationship, a relationship with the environment and moreover we relied on Ideas Koellreutter forming a musical education, a music education that prepared the individual through experiments musical but that caused the or music student is position itself as an individual and to society from with ideas, information and attitudes that could change the way in which he lived basically this was work that was performed, it was a musical for various guests and that brought up this discussion important sonic balance, the environment that we live and the relationship we have with the sound in which we are immersed and whether it can be harmful to our experience if this can damage or not our social relationships and attempting to give suggestions if they might modified, we think it may be modified and improved A second pedagogical experience was titled: Sound of School and these students made a tour on their school sound recording the acoustic characteristics of each environment in the school trying to know better any environment they were living socially sometimes we have a lot of visual stimulus By us being so used to it, we look something sometimes not reflecting to much, we take a viewpoint on this and we are still in front of it the idea was that when we listen, we need a little more time since this activity she listens is not very developed for our senses. There is a sense very developed then that he was to work capture sounds work these sounds and identifies them sounds 10 to 15 seconds 8 sounds were captured and these sounds were transformed in a game where the child should find out which environment he/she was hearing What was the environment? She would have the locate through photographs what environment she was hearing therewith with the creation of this game What we did was lifting the discussion on what was their quality of life, which was their sonic environment at school if it was a friendly environment, a learning environment which was best to do a task, make a lesson, to play then we were mapping the school through sound the audios we collect and it also took to a reflection this environment that we are living every day Well, these two pedagogical actions seek to bring into the school these issues that we see frequently in the media or within universities they are facing artistic awareness but also seeks to promote environmental awareness and sustainability so that students can do and claim and be sensitive to the environment they are living. So that's what I had to say Thank you all.
</field>
<field name="lang">
en-US
</field>

</doc>
<doc>
<field name="id">
Qd-a2rGE1xs
</field>
<field name="link">
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Qd-a2rGE1xs
</field>
<field name="tags">
Israel (Country). TEDx. tedx talks. Politics (Professional Field). ted x. Sustainability (Literary Genre). tedx. ted. Community Service (Organization Sector). Social Change (Literature Subject). TEDxHiriya. Hebrew Language (Human Language). ted talk. ted talks. Activism (Industry). tedx talk
</field>
<field name="categories">
Nonprofits &amp; Activism
</field>
<field name="description">
How does one go from being a naval officer to a waste revolutionist? From his own backyard to 250,000 households in Israel - Amiad Lapidot speaks about the waste separation revolution he ignited in Israel.In the spirit of ideas worth spreading, TEDx is a program of local, self-organized events that bring people together to share a TED-like experience. At a TEDx event, TEDTalks video and live speakers combine to spark deep discussion and connection in a small group. These local, self-organized events are branded TEDx, where x = independently organized TED event. The TED Conference provides general guidance for the TEDx program, but individual TEDx events are self-organized.* (*Subject to certain rules and regulations)
</field>
<field name="title">
The garbage revolution: Amiad Lapidot at TEDxHiriya
</field>
<field name="text">
When I take this apple and let it go, it falls. according to what law? Is there a parliament in the world that can write a law that says that when I drop this apple it will go up rather than fall? There is no such thing. There is an entire system of laws that governs our world. One of our problems is that we ignore this system and it could lead us to a disaster. With this apple alone, I can see two rules. For instance the law of gravity we just mentioned and an additional law, organic matter, that comes form the earth, must return to it. Our earth, all of our dreams, all our hopes and aspirations, they all exist on this planet. One of the things that we don't have an awareness of, is that we today take from the planet much more than it can provide us. My goal in life is to create a model of sustainability. it is a model that will help all of us see how we can live today without hurting the chances of future generations. My name is Amiad Lapidot. This is my youngest son, three months old. What a world are we going to leave him and his generation? How many of you have thought about that question? How many of your are taking responsibility for the planet on which we are living? I often hear people that say that the rate of population growth is the planet's problem. So I took a look, he is the problem? Look how cute he is! Twenty years ago, when I got tho the place where a person decides what to do with himself, I thought that the central issue in the country of Israel, is to keep the borders of the country. So I acted accordingly, joined the army and became a major in the navy to protect its waters. At about the same time, I finished my bachelor's degree in ecology and during my studies I learned that the Mediterranean is the most polluted sea in the world. One of the most polluted places in the Mediterranean is the bay of Haifa. And one of the reasons for that, at least then, is due to the navy base. I learned that actually the daily activities that my friends and I enact, are actually destroying the place we came to protect. I understood that we have to do something, to make a difference. I decided that my goal in life is to make a model of sustainability. A model that will help us live correctly without hurting people in the future generation. That's great as a tag line - but how do you actually do it? What does it mean? All of the creatures in the world, with every passing day, make the world a better place. We are the only ones that with every passing day, the world's situation is worseninig. Let's take the tree as an example, it stands there taking the carbon from the atmosphere uses it to grow leaves and branches - the product of this process is clean oxygen. The tree via its growth process, is cleaning the air. with the roots its cleaning the deep water, with the falling leaves its nurturing the soil. With every passing day, the tree, is making the world a better place. as the tree grows, the situation in the world is getting better. The more trees that we have like that, the situation in the world will become better. Here is a model, that we can truly learn to live according to. There is only one problem, we can't photosynthesize. So let's take an example from other partners we have in the planet, that they also don't know how to photosynthesize, but they, like the tree, with eveey passing day improve the planet's condition. We took a tree, let's take a bird. The bird sits on the branch of the tree, eating the fruits spreading the seeds, so that the next year there will be more trees like that and the bird is doing one additional thing. It stands on the branch, and sings. What a beautiful inspiration we get from a bird on a tree. what a beautiful inspiration we are getting from a tree, or a forrest or a natural grove. What inspiration do we get from an industrial area? From a shopping mall? Or from our homes? Every thing we do in our lives, gives inspiration. In our hands is the opportunity to take responsibility for the inspiration that we create. I decided that i am taking responsibility. i decided that i am going to try to make a difference. I did a few things. I built a model for agriculture that is sustainable, that people from all across the world are coming to study. I built a home that was declared as one of the 10 most green projects in Israel. I have circa 1500 visitors in this home every year, to my wife's displeasure. And I sought to see how I can further my circle of influence and i arrived to garbage. Why garbage? Because we all produce garbage. Garbage is a subject that I really like. Why? Because we all produce garbage, and its the end of the edge of the funnel of our culture. Tell me what your garbage is and I will tell you who you are. Studying the garbage, we can learn a lot about the culture. that's why archaeologists like studying historical garbage. Anyhow, I don't know if you know, but we, the country of Israel, are one of the leading places in the world in the production of garbage. There is no reason for us to be in this place. There is no reason. Almost half of the litter of an average family is the remainders of food. Things that came from the soil, and should return to it. How can we explain the model of sustainability via the apple? This apple has two to important points, where it came from and to where it is going. This apple comes from the tree that grows in the field. The tree grows in the field, absorbing the different materials from the soil, nitrogen, and even water, and puts them in the apple. When we came and took the apple from the tree and along with it we took all the materials from the soil. Now I as a farmer, I am also a farmer, I need to return these materials to the soil. Now what do we do in our culture - we take resources from places like the Dead Sea, in a process that kills the Dead Sea, and put them in a factory that creates chemical fertilizer, in a process that does not do good to the environment, take this fertilizer and put it in our soil in a process that does not do good to the soil at all this materials go down to the deep water, poison the water and those who drink that water, Houston, we have a problem! We have no idea how to run this spaceship that is called Earth. But that's only one side of this apple. We ate this apple and it has become garbage. When we take this garbage and put it in the litter box with the plastic, styrofoam, cans, and everything arrives at the landfill, 50 percent of the weight of the garbage is the organic matter that its rule says that when organic matter begins to die, it decomposes. Except that with all of the condition of the landfill it decomposes in anaerobic conditions, without oxygen we get two negative effects. From one end, we are missing material in our soils, and from the other end we have environmental damage of great degree due to greenhouse effects for instance and it means that next year we'll have a hotter summer and a crazier winter amongst others because we don't know what to do with the garbage we produce. Where is our responsibility for our own garbage? So what can we do? If we take this garbage and we take it to the pile of compost, where compost is actually the best food for plants. Compost is biological material that decomposed in a natural and right process, and returns later and becomes the best possible food for the soil. And we take this compost and with it we'll fertilize the tree and this tree will give us fruit and these fruit will become garbage and this garbage, what will we do it with it, we'll compost it, and what will we do with the compost - we'll fertilize the tree - here is a cycle that can continue on forever - this is sustainability. This is the cycle of life. so simple. So logical. And that's the reason it is so hard to implement it. I decided that I am causing this cycle to move. What did I do: I began in my own community. In my village. I wanted to create a model that will allow people to take responsibility for the garbage they produce. I went house by house in my village. I knocked on the doors and I explained to everyone what I just explained to you here. I gave everyone this garbage can where it is written what you can put inside and what you cannot put inside. And I put a can in their street. And people began separating types of garbage. This can, just for organic matter that was separated at the origin. And look what it looks like, finger licking good. Organic matter, when separated correctly and treated correctly is not a hazard. And myself, with a master's degree from the Technion, a major in the military, life prepared me for this, I began collecting garbage. I took this garbage, to a compost site in my yard, and I produced from it the best possible food for plants, this magnificent compost. This compost is so good that when I grew sweet potatoes, I got one of 6 kilograms. Who says that in order to feed the world population you need chemical fertilizer? Certainly not! You just need to learn to take responsibility. Responsibility for the environment and for the garbage that we produce. This project I began in the village of Kerem Maharal, with 12 families about 10 years ago. Within a year, the entire community was separating garbage. A year later I added two more communities to the project. The following year, 7 more communities. A year later, we arrived at more than 60 places all over Israel in which households take responsibility for the garbage that they produce, and this garbage is not going to a landfill, but rather is being recycled. At this point, a historical meeting with the minister for the protection of the environment my own meeting, with the minister Gilad Erdan. A meeting which he later on declared as a meeting that changed his life. In the meeting it was decided that this will become the general policy in the office of the protection of environment. Today the office and the government of Israel are enacting a policy of separation of garbage at the source. Allowing households to take responsibility for the garbage that we all produce. Today we are looking at 250,000 households that have the possibility to take responsibility for their own garbage. Till today we knew three apples that changed the world. The apple of Adam and Eve, the apple of Newton, and the apple of Steven Jobs. From today we have an additional apple. Get to know the apple that inspires us to take responsibility for what we are doing. Friends, thank you very much.
</field>
<field name="lang">
en-US
</field>

</doc>
<doc>
<field name="id">
mmdohKCeXxo
</field>
<field name="link">
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mmdohKCeXxo
</field>
<field name="tags">
tedx talks. entrepreneurship. ted. TEDxAcademy. innovation. καινοτομία. ted talk. tedx. Greece. Greek. επιχειρηματικότητα. ted talks. ted x. tedx talk. customer service. Business
</field>
<field name="categories">
Education
</field>
<field name="description">
Chairman of the Board of Directors and Chief Executive Officer. Costas Apostolidis is the founder of Raycap Corporation.Raycap is an innovative company in research and product development and In 2011 was awarded from Hellenic Federation of Enterprises (SEV) the 1st Prize for the "STRIKESORB 30-DRM The Ultimate Surge-Protection Technology Reliable, Maintenance-Free, Easy &amp; Practical".Mr Apostolidis is a graduate of the National Technical University of Athens, School of Chemical Engineering, Mining and Metallurgy. He received his MBA of Harvard University and his MSc in Engineering/Hydrometallurgy from McGill University. Prior to founding Raycap, he worked for Raychem Corporation from 1979 to 1987 and for Noranda Mines Canada from 1974 to 1977.In the spirit of ideas worth spreading, TEDx is a program of local, self-organized events that bring people together to share a TED-like experience. At a TEDx event, TEDTalks video and live speakers combine to spark deep discussion and connection in a small group. These local, self-organized events are branded TEDx, where x = independently organized TED event. The TED Conference provides general guidance for the TEDx program, but individual TEDx events are self-organized.* (*Subject to certain rules and regulations)
</field>
<field name="title">
TEDxAcademy - Costas Apostolidis - Breaking the Stereotypes
</field>
<field name="text">
As you can see, these are shoes. They're walking. Taking steps forward. But we can only go forward... if we rid ourselves of certain stereotypes. We have to kick these stereotypes out of our thinking. That's true in every sector, but technology and innovation in particular... advances in leaps and bounds, not one step at a time. Because the amazing dynamics of innovative products and ideas... could help Greece realize its full potential as a country. When we set up the company 24 years ago... it never even crossed our minds that we would be manufacturing innovative products. And yet, today, 80% of the products we sell are innovative. We are active in the electrical protection sector. So what is it we do exactly? We protect equipment from lightning strikes... and the electrical surges that can follow a power cut. As the leading company in this field worldwide, we have 75 patents. As we speak, the latest 4th-generation equipment in mobile telephony... in airport radar systems, solar energy farms, wind farms... on oil rigs and the railways are protected by our products. So how did we get there? From the start, ours wasn't a top-down, management focus. Instead, we tried to provide products which gave added value to the customer. We wanted products that could withstand the most demanding conditions... and that kept on working without needing maintenance. And that's what we did. Along the way, two events would leave their mark on the company. The first was when lightning stopped the conveyor belts... at the lignite mine in Megalopolis. What had happened? A surge from the lightning had destroyed the belts' electrical circuits. Treating the damage as a natural consequence of a weather event... the client began transporting the lignite by truck... which is expensive as well as increasing pollution. But we didn't see it that way. Instead, we studied the problem and found a solution Now the conveyor belts keep working, whatever the weather. The second event that helped mould the company... was when we heard that a man had suffered major burns... in a village in Central Greece... and help couldn't be summoned because the telephone lines were down. This was before mobile phones. So what had happened? In that village... the phone lines ran underneath the power cables... The resulting power surges would blow the fuses on the phone network... which meant the phone company had to send a man out to change them. But the fire was at the weekend, so no technicians were on duty. The result: a man died because help couldn't be called. So what did we do? We improved the fuses. We used semi-conductors which can withstand power surges. So all those villages were equipped with our new fuses.... which never needed changing... and which are still working to this day. So, equipped with this pioneering technology... we produced whole series of ground-breaking products... and filed the patents for the innovative technology they were based on. Then we put them on the market. We started in Greece... but no one was interested, for one simple reason. And the reason is this: although there is so much talk in Greece... about innovation and innovative products... which are terms on absolutely everyone's lips... no one has opened the dictionary to see what 'innovation' actually means. Everyone thinks they can buy the same innovative products... from five or ten companies. The result? They end up buying a run-of-the-mill product that isn't innovative! But we didn't waste any time. We decided to focus on the most cutting-edge technologies... and the most highly developed countries. So we went to the US, Canada, Germany, France, Denmark and Italy... where, as Niki has already told you... we quickly made the leading companies our clients. All this time, we remained oriented in the same direction. Through recessions and booms alike... our focus remained fixed on the customer... on their problems and on solving those problems. We didn't look inwards at ourselves and our company... but outwards at giving added value to our clients. Of course, every company claims to do that. But saying you are client-centric is very easy. Actually doing it is very hard indeed. It's so hard, because you need very clever people working with you... very well-educated people who know their field inside out... and know everything there is to be known about the client's sector, too. Most importantly of all, they have to keep their eye on the ball... and not on the stands. Which means you need good, sound people who aren't egotists. You want to work with people... whose focus is on the client and their problems, not themselves. They also need to be patient... able to work on a client's problem as long as it takes to solve it. Curiosity is essential, too, because that's what leads to innovative solutions. They need to ask what else they can do, for the client and generally. How they can help the client get ahead. And over time, they have to acquire resilience and persistence. And that's only possible when you can quantify the gains to the client. For example, last month... we went to visit a mobile telephony company in Alabama. We were sure they'd be excited with what we had to offer. They listened to what we had to say, but said they were fine as they were. "OK", we said, "but could you give us some data?". How high are your poles, or how many subscribers are there per base station? They gave us the information, we did our calculations... and we got back to them quickly. We said, if you invest 3,000 Euros for this particular base station... our solution will earn you 150,000 back in return. And we had specific figures ready for each and every base station. Of course, we won the contract very soon after that. So this is my point: with figures like that... you really need to get out into the market. When you know a client can invest 3,000 Euros and get a 150,000 return... you can't come up with excuses like "He didn't understand"... "He's from the North or the South", "He's tall or she's blond"! You have to focus on the benefits to the customer... not on finding excuses. Now, our successes... have cut the ground from under a whole bunch of stereotypes. Firstly, that you need connections to get ahead in Greece. That you need access via friends in high places. But as you've seen, we didn't aim at the top. We aimed at the root, at the problem. Another stereotype is that you need money to get ahead. Well, we were all from poor families. We took things one step at a time And when a huge opportunity presented itself to buy a company in the US... we got the facts together... and gave them to our finance director, Nikos Birakis, who was 35 at the time. So when he went to the banks, he didn't go cap in hand... he went with data, and they gave us 8 million Euros to buy the company... and they gave it to us on September 30, 2008... at the very height of the American financial crisis... just two weeks after Lehmann Brothers collapsed! The third stereotype is that Greece doesn't manufacture anything. Well, we manufacture all our products in Drama. And one of our main customers... is a world leader in production. In fact, it introduced the SixSigma system... which allows only one faulty piece... in every million produced. So you can imagine how we felt when they said... they were coming to Drama to inspect our production line! We panicked, grabbed our brooms and started sweeping the road... between their hotel and the factory! They congratulated us: "Your factory is wonderful and so is your workforce." "One electrical engineer, in particular, Fotis Xepapas... is the best we've ever seen". And Fotis was only 35 at the time. And these were extremely experienced people. Another common stereotype is that Greece and quality don't go together If I can give you another example, one of our key clients... whose sales top 50 billion dollars a year... and which manufactures lifts and aircraft engines... told us they worked with 30,000 suppliers... and had problems with all of them... some minor, some major. But we don't have a problem with you... so we came to make sure you were a real, not a virtual, company! And they came and were very enthusiastic with what they found... because we don't perform sample checks on our products... we test all our products. Not because we don't trust statistics... though I can tell you we don't... but because we don't know where a given product will end up. It could end up in my home, or your home... or it could end up in a critical application... in a radar or a vital wind turbine. And that's why we test them all, so we can be 100% sure they'll work. Yet another stereotype has it that Greece conducts no research... and especially in the provinces. Well, we have 75 patents, so that's another stereotype out the window. The fact that we can get to a client in Dusseldorf or Paris... in the same time from Drama or from Athens... has also made it easier to conduct research outside the capital. Another benefit is that, because our researchers work beside the factory... and have access to all its equipment... they can make prototypes for our clients far more quickly and easily. And because we have the space, as well as some sheep... we've been able to build a big solar energy farm... which is the only experimental unit in the world... which produces sizeable amounts of electricity... as well as allowing us to test our products in real-life conditions. Finally, and topically, there is the issue of Greek reliability. We tell our clients they'll have their orders in 3 days... and we say that because we like a challenge... but that isn't to say that we're masochists. And when we say 3 days, we mean 3 days... between receiving an order and delivery to the client in Germany or the US. Because it's very important for the client to know that... our products, which only we sell, will arrive quickly... when they order them. That way, they're free to concentrate on the pressing matters at hand... on helping their company get ahead. That's why quick delivery is so very important. Of course, we live in Greece, not up in the clouds. We know there are strikes and calamities. But we've taken those possibilities into consideration. We don't sit there and say "We know we said 3 days... but it will actually be 5, because there was a strike. That isn't how we do things. When we say 3 days we mean 3 days. Not, you know we said the deficit was going to be 7.6... but because the recession is deeper than we expected... or because Paraguay didn't do so well compared with Uruguay... it's actually going to be 8.5 or 9! When we say 3 days, we mean 3 days. So, you can see that we haven't changed at all down the years... through booms and recessions or the current crisis. We've remained client-oriented. So what is our goal? We want to help our clients get ahead. Not us, them. We want to help our neighbour get ahead... we want to help those around us get ahead... because if they get ahead, they'll take us with them. But to do that, we have to get rid of the stereotypes. We need to throw the stereotypes out the window. Thank you.
</field>
<field name="lang">
en-US
</field>

</doc>
<doc>
<field name="id">
c9GTkycc_EI
</field>
<field name="link">
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=c9GTkycc_EI
</field>
<field name="tags">
tedx. edutainment. entretenimiento. valencia. tedx talk. upv. social change. ted x. activism. TEDxValencia. music. sustainability. castellano. emotional creativity. ted talk. tedxvalencia2012. comercio justo. spanish. ted talks. culture. ted. emotions worth spreading. musica. cultura. creatividad emocional. entertainment. negocio. business. spain. español. tedx talks. bosque de te verde. community
</field>
<field name="categories">
Science &amp; Technology
</field>
<field name="description">
Mapa de la conferencia: http://www.scribd.com/doc/96676010/Nacho-Goberna-EN-LO-PEQUE%E2%80%A2O-PUEDE-ESTAR-LA-RESPUESTANacho Goberna naci\xf3 en San sebasti\xe1n el 30 de julio de 1964. Compositor desde los 17 a\xf1os, ha vivido en primera persona, durante las \xfaltimas tres d\xe9cadas, la err\xe1tica evoluci\xf3n de la industria musical, que nos ha llevado a la preocupante situaci\xf3n actual. M\xfasica y tecnolog\xeda han sido sus grandes pasiones, una combinaci\xf3n de intereses que marca la evoluci\xf3n de su trayectoria. Una trayectoria que le ha llevado no s\xf3lo a crear canciones a bordo de uno de los grupos de referencia del pop espa\xf1ol, La Dama se Esconde, del que fuera l\xedder y bajo cuyo nombre edit\xf3 7 \xe1lbumes, los dos primeros en un sello independiente y cinco en una discogr\xe1fica multinacional, sino a desarrollar, a mediados- finales de los 90, WWW.GET.ES ("Grupos Espa\xf1oles en la Telara\xf1a), el primer portal tem\xe1tico de la internet espa\xf1ola dedicado a la difusi\xf3n de la m\xfasica pop de nuestro pa\xeds, de la que arrancaron webs como la de H\xe9roes del Silencio, el Festival de Benicassim, Subterfuge, etc\xe9tera. M\xe1s adelante, en 2006, cre\xf3 su propio sello discogr\xe1fico, Closer Popnography, donde ha dado cabida hasta hace muy poco a propuestas de calidad, alejadas de la l\xednea m\xe1s comercial. Dentro y en coherencia con ese camino, el \xfaltimo paso, donde a\xfana toda su creatividad y la experiencia acumulada, es Unbosquedeteverde.com, que toma su nombre de su segundo disco en solitario, "Un bosque de t\xe9 verde", de 2010. Se trata de un nuevo modo de vivir la m\xfasica, de una propuesta realizada en solitario, al margen de la industria y de los modos de distribuci\xf3n al uso. El compositor aprovecha las herramientas, vers\xe1tiles, potentes y asequibles, que ofrecen Internet y las nuevas tecnolog\xedas, para interactuar con sus seguidores, con aquellos que por suscripci\xf3n han decidido compartir un trozo de ese "refugio", como \xe9l lo denomina, de esa "caba\xf1a en el Bosque". Canciones in\xe9ditas, grabaciones de conciertos en vivo, videoclips, escritos, fotograf\xedas... La f\xf3rmula id\xf3nea para abrir las distintas ventanas de su sensibilidad y para  poner en pie un modelo de intercambio cultural justo, una original e innovadora manera de compartir, de relacionarse, de desarrollar su trabajo sin prejuicios y al margen de los convencionalismos. Una respuesta, en fin, a un mercado anquilosado en la repetici\xf3n de usos y costumbres.In the spirit of ideas worth spreading, TEDx is a program of local, self-organized events that bring people together to share a TED-like experience. At a TEDx event, TEDTalks video and live speakers combine to spark deep discussion and connection in a small group. These local, self-organized events are branded TEDx, where x = independently organized TED event. The TED Conference provides general guidance for the TEDx program, but individual TEDx events are self-organized.* (*Subject to certain rules and regulations)
</field>
<field name="title">
Comercio Justo Aplicado a la Distribuci\xf3n Musical: Nacho Goberna at TEDxValencia
</field>
<field name="text">
So let's dedicate our lives to conceiving it These words appear in Thoreau's fantastic book Walden (Life in the Woods) Thoreau was a man who around the middle of the 19th century said "no" to a lot of things Basically, what he did throughout his life was refuse to accept a series of premises which it seemed ought to be followed because they didn't make him feel fulfilled and he chose the little over the big he chose the natural over industry he chose seclusion over big cities And that's not all he even went to live for a year in a little cabin he built himself in a small forest near Massachusetts Re-reading that book was what made me think of unbosquedeteverde.com my website after noticing over several years that the music industry was unable even to offer me the possibility of showing my work and developing it I decided the time had come to say no to those ideas and look for a small place a place where I could build with my own hands like Thoreau did with his cabin and making use, in my case of free or low-cost internet tools a place where I could show what I do show my creative work to anyone who might be interested or feel close to my way of doing saying composing From there Perhaps it's best if we go to the beginning What is the music industry? How is it structured? It's very simple I've been with 'The Lady Hides' for many years and afterwards on my own I know the map very well I know where they're heading And the music industry basically functions, let's say between the two main cornerstones, which are on the one hand, the artist, and on the other, the follower There's a series of extras, a series of characters of compartments which are: firstly the records then the distributor, which can be analogue or digital and subsequently the shop a long journey for the income the work generates to get to the artist And what happens? Well, it happens what usually happens when journeys are very long and what is produced generates very little money Because a song, usually, does not produce a flood of cash Everything the song generates gets siphoned off along the way and in the end I, and many other artists, the majority in fact what our songs produce in the end comes to us in drips and we barely get to touch what that song generates because it gets lost along the way Getting away from that was the basis on which I wanted to build "A green tea forest" And one of the things I initially thought about was that much-used term 'crowdfunding' Not long ago, crowdfunding was mentioned in a national newspaper and they translated it as Microfinancing or microsponsorship microfinancing, okay, I agree with that But microfinancing has always existed in music because in the end, always, before, now, and ever after we artists gain from small acts of will by the people who buy CDs who buy concert tickets So okay, I accept it, I'm using it, but I don't think it's anything new The other one, microsponsorship. That, to put it mildly, winds me up because it sounds a bit like charity And I wasn't considering that under any circumstances It's not about people in some way doing you a favour No. I don't like that aspect, or that translation of crowd funding And all of this lead me, quite naturally, to the concept of fair trade. A concept which, from my point of view is beautiful. It's healthy. It's balanced And it can be applied to many fields, but curiously in culture and music As far as I know, it's not being used Why not apply fair trade to culture, and in this case to music, which is what I know best? Fair trade means a voluntary, direct relationship between the composer and the person who enjoys the composition with no intermediaries whatsoever out with added value out with the filters and leaks which siphon off what the server brings in, which by rights should go to the artist And in comes a mutual commitment a symbiotic relationship those of us who make music are really as important as those who receive the music because without either of those two agents, the thing breaks down it stops being possible I reject subsidies. Of course. We're not talking about subsidies. We're talking about trade. On the other hand, we have advanced payment. In my case I opted for subscription to stop producers looking for other sources of funding and so they, or we in this case, don't decide to stop making songs Quality and exclusivity of the content definitively, in a web environment that we create because we think we can offer a lot of things that don't fit inside a physical CD as is bought in a shop. And nor do they fit when you hear a song in a digital supermarket. And, finally, the price you pay (and I think this is important, and worth mentioning) allows for decent living conditions and recognises the work and cost of what is made, what is generated, what is produced. I've made more than one hundred songs in my life, released. And I assure you that making songs is a joy. I can't imagine a more beautiful thing. But it's also true that it takes time, requires effort and dedication. It is important to recognise that. That comes into fair trade and that comes into "a forest". At the start of "a forest", more than a year ago one of the first registered users sent me an email at 8:15am and I answered at the 8:20am and he in turn replied, saying "a musician who gets up early!" And I said "carai!" I can assure you that a lot of people who make songs, who work in music, not just me, the vast majority (and please forget about the big stars, the ones that dazzle) We know as well as you what it means to get up early. What it means to get up at eight or nine, like any working person. We're no different in that. We're the same. People trying to do an activity that fulfils us as best we can. And for it to be received, as in fact it is received, by the people who enjoy what we do. Basically, all these approaches dumped into "A Forest of Green Tea" dumped into the web, from my point of view makes it possible, and it's happening with "A Forest of Grean Tea", For sustainability to get ever closer to us, the artists And that allows us, besides, two very important things, As soon as we get rid of hindrances, get out of our bonds whatever might inhibit us at any time, What happens? something very cool happens: we are more free to create. We don't have to depend on anyone We don't have to ask for opinion's opinion We can bring out whatever we feel like from in here. And that, from my point of view, enriches the creative process. And, secondly, this kind of approach allows us to earn a living, not only for the big stars and to practice music and develop creative work. It allows for heterodoxy, for minority interests, for different approaches. In short, what it does is enrich the music scene and make it possible for more and different kinds of approach to sustain themselves and for people to be able to choose more freely too All of this is great. The truth is that it's great. I'm thrilled with this year of "A Forest of Green Tea". But, are there problems? Yes, true, there are problems and the problems, almost all of them, come from something very human: the word "prejudices" That thing, that word, that sensation that we have and that prevents us from occasionally looking a little further than our own nose. Prejudices, for exemple, from the media and prejudices from concert halls I know an artist who, some years ago, told me, an artist who edited his own records, that he sent e-mails with information about his records and his concerts to the press and to the concert halls and they all just ignored him so he decided to invent a manager he decided to create a fictional character and he would write through this character to the media and the concert halls and, what's more, he decided to create an English character and modified the language so it would seem like an English person, a perfect speaker of BBC English, was sending his information, though really it was him. and, what a surprise surprise, the people who never replied, some of them, not the whole lot, you can't have everything but some of them started to show an interest exactly the same stuff, just with typos and spelling mistakes but written under a false name generated the interest that he wasn't able to get before There are prejudices in the press and there are prejudices in concert halls when it is the author talking about his own work And why is that? Isn't it far more defensible far more admirable, an author who fights from the trenches, from the beginning, who defends his work, who spreads it, than one who simply hides behind a representative of a label who was maybe working in marketing for a tobacco company the month before? And I'm not making this up. I experienced it myself with "The Lady Hides" What is more admirable? Who should be paid more attention? The protagonist? Or the representative of the protagonist? Then there is the prejudice of the physical CD A few times recently I've contacted some media outlets and I've said to them "Ill send you a link. You'll be able to hear the song in CD quality..." "Ah, no, no, no. I want a CD" What century are we in? If we're talking about what we want, I want a CD too but the point is that nowadays the quality of the sound doesn't only have to do with the CD and the ease of use doesn't depend only on the CD There's something else, don't you think? They have to forget about all those prejudices. I hope they do. And lastly, there are the prejudices of the followers and the artists Both share one thing in common. We tend to undervalue to sell ourselves, the artists, short, and the followers undervalue those who talk about what they do in the first person the creative process defended by oneself has less value so, or I'm an idiot, which I don't doubt I am, or that is exactly the opposite to what it should be If one is first, he is more important than if he is hiding behind something of a gear, industry, label or whatever you want to call it in the end, we come back to Thoreau. That great man said "a man must find his occasions in himself" "I did not wish to take a cabin passage, but rather to go before the mast and on the deck of the world. I do not wish to go below now" This thing, said by him, and a thousend times better than anything I could say, is what "a Forest of Green Tea" means. We, the artists, the musicians, the composers, accepting, not only with pleasure, but with a huge smile that our way might lie in taking charge of everything not only composing songs, which is great, but also the rest and relating to those who give sense to what we do the followers, directly. As I said at the beginning: without added value, interference, or noise My grandfather was a seaman. In the twenties, at the end of the twenties of the 20th Century he managed, with a little rickety boat of which he was captain and sailor both he managed to make his work on the sea sustainable His boat was one of the smallest ones in the Ria de Vigo But often it arrived full and he made it possible for his family, through his work and within that small environment of a family company, he managed to get his family ahead Meanwhile, the boats of those days, bigger and more modern had problems, they arrived with a half load, and they couldn't pay their employees mi grandfather managed to make something sustainable from something small Why can't I? why can't we do it? authors and musicians It's time, definitely It's time for us, those who share this planet with all of you, who make songs who dedicate a lot of time to making songs, and we want to do it and we're happy doing it it's time for us to be not only captains, which is right and very elegant but also to be the sailors of our own creative development and become the protagonists of our own legitimate quest for sustainability in our life based on the work we like to do and if we don't do it, who is going to do it? is the music industry going to do it? I bet my whole Star Trek DVD collection they won't Thank you very much
</field>
<field name="lang">
en-US
</field>

</doc>
<doc>
<field name="id">
OjPvOiFfhlc
</field>
<field name="link">
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OjPvOiFfhlc
</field>
<field name="tags">
learning. Gever Tulley. learning through building. Tinkering School. učenie sa. netradičný. kids. innovative school. children. ted x. Brightworks. tedx talk. konštruovanie. budovanie. deti. ted. alternative education. ted talk. alternatívne vzdelávanie. ted talks. TEDxBratislava. unconventional educator. alternatívna škola. tedx. Bratislava. tedx talks. education. majstrovanie. Slovakia. trieda. novátorská škola. hands-on learning. pedagóg. vzdelávanie
</field>
<field name="categories">
Education
</field>
<field name="description">
(popis v Sloven\u010dine ni\u017e\u0161ie)Gever Tulley is a world renowned author, TED speaker and founder of Brightworks -- a one of a kind innovative school in San Francisco, California. Gever is a self-taught computer scientist with no formal education who holds multiple technology patents, Gever's expertise is really in... thinking. He has taught workshops and made presentations to both kids and adults, around the world. He has spoken at TED, twice, written articles for MAKE:, and authored the book Fifty Dangerous Things (you should let your children do). Back in 2005 he founded a summer program called Tinkering School in order to learn how children become competent and to explore the notion that kids can build anything, and through building, learn anything. This experience then led to opening Brightworks in 2011 -- a unique school that reimagines K-12 education. By taking the best practices from both early childhood education and hands-on, project-based experiential learning, the school strives to meet students' needs in a flexible, mixed-age environment that breaks the traditional walls between school and the community outside the classroom.For more about Gever Tulley and the Brightworks school see http://www.gevertulley.com/ and http://www.brightworks.org/Scroll down for more about TEDxGever Tulley je svetovo presl\xe1ven\xfd autor, TED re\u010dn\xedk a zakladate\u013e Brightworks - inovat\xedvnej \u0161koly jedinej svojho druhu, v San Franciscu v Kalifornii. Gever je samouk, po\u010d\xedta\u010dov\xfd odborn\xedk bez form\xe1lneho vzdelania, ktor\xfd m\xe1 viacero technologick\xfdch patentov. Geverova expert\xedza je vlastne v .. myslen\xed.Vyu\u010doval semin\xe1re a robil prezent\xe1cie pre deti i dospel\xfdch po celom svete. Dvakr\xe1t hovoril na TEDe, nap\xedsal \u010dl\xe1nky pre MAKE a nap\xedsal knihu P\xe4\u0165desiat nebezpe\u010dn\xfdch vec\xed (ktor\xe9 by ste mali necha\u0165 svoje deti). V roku 2005 zalo\u017eil letn\xfd program s n\xe1zvom Tinkering school, kde sa deti m\xf4\u017eu nau\u010di\u0165, ako by\u0165 kompetentn\xe9 a maj\xfa \u0161ancu zisti\u0165, \u017ee deti m\xf4\u017eu postavi\u0165 \u010doko\u013evek a cez stavanie sa aj ve\u013ea nau\u010di\u0165. T\xe1to sk\xfasenos\u0165 ho n\xe1sledne viedla v roku 2011 k otvoreniu Brightworks - jedine\u010dn\xe1 \u0161kola, ktor\xe1 men\xed vzdel\xe1vanie. Pomocou osved\u010den\xfdch postupov z pred\u0161kolsk\xe9ho vzdel\xe1vania a na z\xe1klade projektov zalo\u017een\xfdch na ru\u010dn\xfdch pr\xe1cach vytv\xe1ra z\xe1\u017eitkov\xe9 u\u010denie, \u010d\xedm sa \u0161kola sa sna\u017e\xed vyhovie\u0165 potreb\xe1m \u0161tudentov vo flexibilnom, vekovo zmie\u0161anom prostred\xed, ktor\xe9 nar\xfa\u0161a tradi\u010dn\xe9 m\xfary medzi \u0161kolou a komunitou.About TEDx:In the spirit of ideas worth spreading, TEDx is a program of local, self-organized events that bring people together to share a TED-like experience. At a TEDx event, TEDTalks video and live speakers combine to spark deep discussion and connection in a small group. These local, self-organized events are branded TEDx, where x = independently organized TED event. The TED Conference provides general guidance for the TEDx program, but individual TEDx events are self-organized.* (*Subject to certain rules and regulations)
</field>
<field name="title">
TEDxBratislava - Gever TULLEY - Secrets of engagement-based learning
</field>
<field name="text">
What aápleasure. What an amazing TEDx! So imagine you had an opportunity in your life to consider the question of education without looking at all of the restrictions and the complexities that come with introducing education to a country like yours. Imagine you lived in a mythical places like California, where there were no laws about what kind of education you could create. If you could imagine the best possible place for children to learn. If you could imagine the most incredible learning experiences day after day. and if you could imagine starting a school with two questions in your mind - two powerful questions that would shape how you rethought education and those two questions: Where does competence come from? How do people become those kind of people that we admire, who can take on any new challenge, like Ahmed (Coucha)and his TEDxCairo - his little change that was part of that revolution of Arab spring. How do people become like Zuzana (Kierulfova) and her passion about such simple thing like mud that transforms lives and transforms how people think about housing. And the other question is: Are there possibly experiences that children have that predispose them to heroic behavior later in life? Is there something about what happens in childhood that makes you that kind of person? So I started my summer camp with those two questions. And this was my summer camp. I made it for me to answer questions. This was in fact my own private laboratory where I could experiment on other people's children. And because it was my camp we built stuff. This is what I do when I have time for my self and this was a passion I could share with children, in this context. We built a roller coaster with 20 meters, no 30 meters of track. We built incredible cars that you power by rowing. And as we were doing this we started to have some fundamental realizations about how children learn. And one of them, it seems so obvious, but it's almost gone from education - from traditional education. And I'll tell you now and when you see it you'll remember how obvious this is. We think with our hands. It's true. 30% of our brains is dedicated to processing information from our hands. Just like those cockroaches we sense the world through these and we make sense of the world through these. Ideas that we form in our heads we often metaphorically shape with our hands. We see the same parts of our brain light up. And in fact, if you pick something up, you probably have something in your hand right now that you can use, I want you to turn to the person next to you and poke them with it. Go on! OK. Put that object down and poke them with your finger. OK. If we had you in one of those giant machines with the magnetic doughnut and we were looking at the activity in your brain, the exact same parts of the brain would light up whether I poke you with the thing or I poke you with my finger. And that's because our brains are wired for tools - for things that we put in our hands. When I put this in my hand my brain reshapes to include the end of this thing as part of my body and it doesn't matter if this is a few centimeters long, if it's aápencil, or it's two meters long. If I poke someone with a two meter stick my body is extended - the model I have in the my brain of my very own body - is extended to the end of that stick. You should let your children play with sticks. Itĺs good for the brain. Such a simple idea and yet in classrooms we ask children to sit in desks and use the exact same tools hour after hour after hour, never getting a chance to expand their brains with the use of different tools. We have built some amazing stuff at Tinkering School. When you give children aáchance to both come up with an idea, build it and test it in the real world - to make a boat that might sink, not just their minds but their hearts are involved in that project. They are passionate about the result. So we discovered a new idea: Create a meaningful experience and the learning will follow! What that means is that if you focus first, before you even think about curriculum, before you worry about math, reading, writing if you focus on designing the experience the rest of it you get for free. So what would a school be like if it came from a place where children could build airplanes and fly them? My little summer camp became famous and I got to speak on the main stage at TED. This was a transformative moment for me. My little camp which I ran at my house became world famous. I got invited to speak to educators around the world about this little idea. And s I spoke to them I realized there were parts missing from my idea. It couldn't be aáschool. I had some good parts and I had some bad parts. And working with these educators in places literally as far away as Bahrain and as close to home as San Francisco - my nearest city - these incredible people shared these ideas and we put together something that made sense. And I want you to know I'm not an educator by training. I come from the world of computer technology. Iáused to manage and innovation group at Adobe, which was a great job and I left it for this. So I'm the guy who teaches children how to make perfectly round balls of sand. And now I'm going to make them out of mud. But this idea that we started to frame with these educators was big and complicated. And in order to understand it I had to draw it, because that's how I think and Iĺm gonna draw it for you right now. So, if the standard traditional pedagogical unit of a traditional school is that day divided into these forty five minute periods - a little bit of math, a little bit of science, a little bit of history, a little bit aálunch, a little bit of physical education, ... If that's how we think of children's education now I want you to consider a new pedagogical unit. We call it the Arc. Every Arc has aátheme - a guiding idea which shapes how we create the education for the children. For this example Iĺm going to use wind. Wind - such a common element of our lives, but if we look at it closely, there's so much that we can explore and that's what we do. We call this first phase of the Arc EXPLORATION. and in this phase we create aálandscape for the children to explore and we populate this landscape with ideas about wind that are represented by actual people and things. Learning should be tangible. So we invite somebody in who generates power using wind. You guys do a lot of that here. We invite somebody who uses wind to transport goods around the world or studied how that happened. We bring in artists who work with wind to create sculptures. We bring scientists in who study the meteorological sources of wind and the effects of wind. And through this landscape we take the children on aájourney. They meet these people, they work with these ideas, they see the actual thing in real life. We leave the school all the time. The children become inspired by these ideas and we capture that inspiration. They work with a collaborator - an adult what you would call aáteacher - to create aádeclaration. This declaration is the transition from our EXPLORATION phase into a new phase. Each of these declarations is aáclear statement about what they intend to build, or do, or practice, or learn about in this next phase. We call this phase EXPRESSION. This is not just about building. It could be theater, it could be singing, it could be writing, it could be anything, but we want them to express some new understanding about wind. A design build practice to create aánew kind of a windmill. The exploration of aáhypothesis about the effect of wind in a certain environment - a micro climate. A series of practicing of writing and performing songs and building a stage ends in a performance that the kids have created about wind. That performance happens in the last Arc... I mean the last phase of our Arc. We call it EXPOSITION - a chance to show the world their understanding of wind. We open the doors of the school and strangers flood in. They come from other schools, they are friends of the experts that we've been working with, they are friends of the parents and they are the parents themselves and we put on aáshow. We have a science museum of wind. We have aápoetry museum of wind. And then all of that notes and progress and the daily reflections get compiled together to create - in a moment of reflection - aáportfolio. A clear description of what they learned in this project, the decisions that they made and the kinds of things they tried. This portfolio,over the course of their lives at my school, begins to accumulate projects and when they graduate, if they started with us in kindergarten, they'll have done 60 projects taken from that moment of inspiration all the way to completion. We give this back to them when they walk out the door and they take that right to aáuniversity. We've contacted some of the highest universities in the United States, explained how our school works and they say: Yes! We will take those people who know how to get things done, how of work with their own ideas. So you're asking yourself: What does a school like this really look like? Let's have a peak at Brightworks. Last night I collected images that were put on our blog for Wednesday. This is a peek into our school three days ago. We're in the end of an EXPRESSION phase. Here's Alexander, cutting a piece of steel to be the axle of a seven person peddle powered camper where that children will sleep and drive the camper themselves on a three day camping trip next week. Here's his brother Daniel working with one of the experts in bicycle design who has come in to share his time with children. Twenty hours over the course of this EXPLORATION I mean EXPRESSION phrase. Here's their teammate Zada working to shape and take the sharp edges off that piece of steel. Zada is ten years old. Here are the youngest children of our school - 6 and 7 years old working on creating eggs - paper machete eggs - for a play that they're doing about the life cycle of birds. Lola and Bruno. Here are the kids going to lunch. They've decided to bring the chickens that the youngest children hatched as part of their exploration of the life cycle of birds. Theyĺre taking them to the park because the chickens don't get enough outdoor time. Here are ten, eleven - sorry nine, ten and eleven year olds rehearsing a play that they've been working on now for two weeks. In order to do the play, because there are special effects involved, they had to create their own theater. This is a 400 pound stage it took the entire school to lower to the ground. Having put it down they had to immediately test it. Occasionally, when you look at your own pedagogy, you have to know when to put it aside. So we have this phrase we use sometimes in our school: ôScrew the Arc, make the cheese!ö We invented this because a few weeks ago we had an opportunity to work with the world-famous cheese maker. It didn't fit into our Arc, which was around the topic of locomotion - energy applied to move in aásingle direction. What does that have to do with cheese? Absolutely nothing! But you cannot say no when you have an opportunity to meet with someone who can explain to children the history of cheese in four hours and in doing so make cheese with children. Similarly, when it became apparent that the little eggs were starting to hatch, for those chickens that we were taking to the park, the children demanded and organized an overnight vigil to watch those eggs hatch. For the first time in our history almost all of the student body slept in the school. The next day - aácelebration, and one baby chick. Educators come from around the world to visit our school. This is Steve Davee from the world-famous Opal School in Portland in the North America. Climbing on a structure built by twelve year olds who had just recently raised these giant tree trunks up against the wall and then screened two-by-fours to them to create a bike rack. The bike rack never came into existence - it was too much fun to climb. We treat the city as an extension of our school. Using bicycles and buses we are trying to get the children to see the world as a place of learning. This is our school and this is our dream. We make a lot of mistakes. We are constantly making mistakes and so are the children. Working with the collaborators we are creating our school together. It is amazing, it is frustrating and it is the most rewarding work I've ever done. Thank you very much.
</field>
<field name="lang">
en-US
</field>

</doc>
<doc>
<field name="id">
_siqiFqfZnw
</field>
<field name="link">
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_siqiFqfZnw
</field>
<field name="tags">
Taiwan. learning beyond. 台灣. ted talk. 2013. TEDx. tedx talks. taking off. ted x. 翻轉. carrying on. 何處不學堂. 藝術發新枝. Lakshmi Pratury. 人生不設限. 與大地和解. 新世代啟程. tedx. TEDxTaipei. tedx talk. 正向的破壞. passing on. ink conference. flip. breaking through. living together. ted. ted talks
</field>
<field name="categories">
Education
</field>
<field name="description">
Translated into Chinese by Raquel Deng  \u2022  Reviewed by Michelle LoLakshmi Pratury brought TED to India in 2009. In 2010, She curated and hosted The INK Conference in association with TED. In the same year, she was featured in the list of "100 Most Powerful Women" by Forbes Asian. She was also a leading force at the American India Foundation (AIF) where she helped raise $30M in five years to channel toward development activities in India.Pratury founded the Digital Equalizer, which brought technology education to over 100,000 children and 2,000 teachers in India. Prior to becoming a social entrepreneur, her career spanned across technology and venture capital. She is a contributor to the National Public Radio, has published articles in the San Jose Mercury, San Francisco Chronicle, Mint, and acted in local (US) theaters. Pratury has also spoken at high profile conferences such as TED in the US, DLD in Germany and IIM Bangalore.Lakshmi Pratury \u57282009\u5e74\u5c07TED\u5e36\u9032\u5370\u5ea6\uff0c\u9694\u5e74\u5ef6\u7e8cTED \u5728\u5370\u5ea6\u7684\u5f71\u97ff\u529b\uff0c\u5275\u8fa6\u4e86The INK Conference\u3002\u540c\u5e74\u88ab\u4e9e\u6d32\u5bcc\u6bd4\u58eb\u8a55\u9078\u70ba\u300c2010\u5e74\u5ea6\u767e\u5927\u6b0a\u5a01\u5973\u6027\u300d\u3002\u5979\u66fe\u7d93\u5728\u7f8e\u570b\u5370\u5ea6\u57fa\u91d1\u6703 (American India Foundation) \u64d4\u4efb\u8981\u89d2\uff0c\u4e26\u5728\u4e94\u5e74\u5167\u7684\u70ba\u5370\u5ea6\u52df\u96c6\u4e86\u4e09\u5343\u842c\u7f8e\u5143\u7684\u5efa\u8a2d\u7d93\u8cbb\u3002\u5979\u5275\u8fa6\u4e86Digital Equalizer\uff0c\u5c07\u79d1\u6280\u6559\u80b2\u5e36\u7d66\u8fd1\u5341\u842c\u540d\u5b78\u7ae5\u548c\u5169\u5343\u540d\u6559\u5e2b\u3002\u6210\u70ba\u793e\u6703\u4f01\u696d\u5bb6\u4e4b\u524d\uff0cPratury \u66fe\u4efb\u8077\u65bc\u79d1\u6280\u696d\u548c\u5275\u6295\u516c\u53f8\uff0c\u4e5f\u662fNational Public Radio\u3001San Jose Mercury\u3001San Francisco Chronicle\u3001Mint\u7b49\u5a92\u9ad4\u7684\u5b9a\u671f\u64b0\u7a3f\u4eba\u3002Pratury \u66fe\u662fTED\u3001\u5fb7\u570b\u7684DLD\u4ee5\u53ca\u73ed\u52a0\u7f85\u723eIIM\u7b49\u8ad6\u58c7\u7684\u8b1b\u8005\u3002TEDxTaipei \u5b98\u7db2\uff1ahttp://tedxtaipei.com/TEDxTaiepi \u5b98\u65b9\u81c9\u66f8\uff1ahttps://www.facebook.com/TEDxTaipeiTEDxTaiepi Google+\uff1ahttp://goo.gl/UAIjDLTEDxTaipei 2013 - \u7ffb\u8f49Fl!p : http://2013.tedxtaipei.com/In the spirit of ideas worth spreading, TEDx is a program of local, self-organized events that bring people together to share a TED-like experience. At a TEDx event, TEDTalks video and live speakers combine to spark deep discussion and connection in a small group. These local, self-organized events are branded TEDx, where x = independently organized TED event. The TED Conference provides general guidance for the TEDx program, but individual TEDx events are self-organized.* (*Subject to certain rules and regulations)
</field>
<field name="title">
Learn to let go and keep on: Lakshmi Pratury at TEDxTaipei 2013
</field>
<field name="text">
1 00:00:16,186 --&amp;gt; 00:00:18,041 You know we all know that 2 00:00:18,041 --&amp;gt; 00:00:21,494 we are moving from a very, very industrial economy 3 00:00:21,494 --&amp;gt; 00:00:24,999 to a knowledge economy, to a creative economy. 4 00:00:24,999 --&amp;gt; 00:00:27,565 But what does this really mean? 5 00:00:27,565 --&amp;gt; 00:00:32,604 How do we learn to prepare for this new economy? 6 00:00:32,604 --&amp;gt; 00:00:34,624 The first thing we need to figure out is: 7 00:00:34,624 --&amp;gt; 00:00:37,041 we need to create a community of people, 8 00:00:37,041 --&amp;gt; 00:00:39,743 people that are sitting right here, 9 00:00:39,743 --&amp;gt; 00:00:42,414 to open up our imagination 10 00:00:42,414 --&amp;gt; 00:00:46,290 and then turn our imagination into impact. 11 00:00:46,290 --&amp;gt; 00:00:50,757 Now even that, what does 'that' mean? 12 00:00:50,757 --&amp;gt; 00:00:53,325 I have a confession to make. 13 00:00:53,325 --&amp;gt; 00:00:55,477 I work at Intel, for many years. 14 00:00:55,477 --&amp;gt; 00:00:56,977 And I am from India. 15 00:00:56,977 --&amp;gt; 00:01:00,598 So the only two ways I know how to learn 16 00:01:00,598 --&amp;gt; 00:01:03,001 is either through acronyms, 17 00:01:03,001 --&amp;gt; 00:01:04,668 or through stories. 18 00:01:04,668 --&amp;gt; 00:01:07,004 That's it. I can't learn any other way. 19 00:01:07,004 --&amp;gt; 00:01:11,441 So I thought I will subject to you the way I learn. 20 00:01:11,441 --&amp;gt; 00:01:14,144 So A.P.P.S. 21 00:01:14,144 --&amp;gt; 00:01:16,113 Everybody has apps these days. 22 00:01:16,113 --&amp;gt; 00:01:17,729 There's an app for waking up, 23 00:01:17,729 --&amp;gt; 00:01:19,351 app for sleeping app, app for everything. 24 00:01:19,351 --&amp;gt; 00:01:21,893 But let me tell you my definition of apps. 25 00:01:21,893 --&amp;gt; 00:01:23,423 You know in Indian mythology, 26 00:01:23,423 --&amp;gt; 00:01:25,424 or in Indian philosophy, 27 00:01:25,424 --&amp;gt; 00:01:27,790 we said that there are four stages of life. 28 00:01:27,790 --&amp;gt; 00:01:30,312 There's childhood, youth, 29 00:01:30,312 --&amp;gt; 00:01:33,199 at age where you are responsible, you're head of the household. 30 00:01:33,199 --&amp;gt; 00:01:35,311 and then ultimately Nirvana. 31 00:01:35,311 --&amp;gt; 00:01:39,977 You know, you retire and then you make your final journey. 32 00:01:39,977 --&amp;gt; 00:01:45,663 So if you think of, what does each of this age entail? 33 00:01:45,663 --&amp;gt; 00:01:49,314 So the first thing is A.P.P.S. In the A, is 34 00:01:49,314 --&amp;gt; 00:01:51,080 Ask. 35 00:01:51,080 --&amp;gt; 00:01:53,117 What does a child do all the time? 36 00:01:53,117 --&amp;gt; 00:01:54,080 They keep asking. 37 00:01:54,080 --&amp;gt; 00:01:54,986 Why is the sky blue? 38 00:01:54,986 --&amp;gt; 00:01:55,913 Why are we going there? 39 00:01:55,913 --&amp;gt; 00:01:57,080 Why are we not going there? 40 00:01:57,080 --&amp;gt; 00:01:58,122 Are we there yet? 41 00:01:58,122 --&amp;gt; 00:02:00,524 Why? Why? Why? Why? Why? 42 00:02:00,524 --&amp;gt; 00:02:02,498 They keep asking. 43 00:02:02,498 --&amp;gt; 00:02:05,581 Because that's the way they learn. 44 00:02:05,581 --&amp;gt; 00:02:08,081 And the next thing is Practice. 45 00:02:08,081 --&amp;gt; 00:02:09,869 You know a kid gets up, walks, falls down, 46 00:02:09,869 --&amp;gt; 00:02:13,830 gets up, walks, falls down, and that's how they learn. 47 00:02:13,830 --&amp;gt; 00:02:19,247 We need to practice our ideas over and over and over again. 48 00:02:19,247 --&amp;gt; 00:02:22,780 And then, we have to become the head of the household. 49 00:02:22,780 --&amp;gt; 00:02:24,998 We have to figure out how our ideas are gonna 50 00:02:24,998 --&amp;gt; 00:02:28,747 actually create an impact out there and make a profit, 51 00:02:28,747 --&amp;gt; 00:02:32,831 so that we have the whole world sustainable around us. 52 00:02:32,831 --&amp;gt; 00:02:37,413 And finally, the S is the most important part of this. 53 00:02:37,413 --&amp;gt; 00:02:41,298 is that every learning has a stage 54 00:02:41,298 --&amp;gt; 00:02:45,164 when you need to Surrender to the next generation. 55 00:02:45,164 --&amp;gt; 00:02:48,940 Because otherwise you'll never let someone else come. 56 00:02:48,940 --&amp;gt; 00:02:50,307 And when I say next generation, 57 00:02:50,307 --&amp;gt; 00:02:53,829 I don't mean somebody younger necessarily 58 00:02:53,829 --&amp;gt; 00:02:57,163 but maybe the next person who has been working with you. 59 00:02:57,163 --&amp;gt; 00:03:00,384 So you need to know when to complete that. 60 00:03:00,384 --&amp;gt; 00:03:01,747 So in this A.P.P.S, 61 00:03:01,747 --&amp;gt; 00:03:05,389 You know we ask, we practice, we create a profit, 62 00:03:05,389 --&amp;gt; 00:03:06,223 we surrender. 63 00:03:06,223 --&amp;gt; 00:03:10,961 Now, in the past, we used to do this only once in our lifetime. 64 00:03:10,961 --&amp;gt; 00:03:14,632 Then, maybe in my generation, we do it three or four times. 65 00:03:14,632 --&amp;gt; 00:03:17,569 But in the new generation that's coming out, 66 00:03:17,569 --&amp;gt; 00:03:19,270 including all of us who is here 67 00:03:19,270 --&amp;gt; 00:03:21,905 who's planing to live for another 20, 30 years, 68 00:03:21,905 --&amp;gt; 00:03:24,163 we rather learn how to do this 69 00:03:24,163 --&amp;gt; 00:03:27,379 over and over and over again. 70 00:03:27,379 --&amp;gt; 00:03:30,248 So there is a circle there with no particular arrows 71 00:03:30,248 --&amp;gt; 00:03:32,413 because it's an infinite "do loop". 72 00:03:32,413 --&amp;gt; 00:03:34,284 We have to ask, we have to practice, 73 00:03:34,284 --&amp;gt; 00:03:35,388 we have to profit from it, 74 00:03:35,388 --&amp;gt; 00:03:38,958 we have surrender ourselves. Go on to the new idea. 75 00:03:38,958 --&amp;gt; 00:03:41,662 And this is a paradigm 76 00:03:41,662 --&amp;gt; 00:03:45,436 of the new generation of the new economy is that 77 00:03:45,436 --&amp;gt; 00:03:46,396 we have to learn to let go and keep on. 78 00:03:46,396 --&amp;gt; 00:03:53,269 And to remember this I'll tell you one quick story. 79 00:03:53,269 --&amp;gt; 00:03:55,269 There is a movie called "6 Degrees of Separation" 80 00:03:55,269 --&amp;gt; 00:03:57,808 which is one of my favorite movies. 81 00:03:57,808 --&amp;gt; 00:04:00,197 And in that, you know, Donald Sutherland is telling 82 00:04:00,197 --&amp;gt; 00:04:04,031 this story of this teacher of his child. 83 00:04:04,031 --&amp;gt; 00:04:06,113 Since I go to my child's school, 84 00:04:06,113 --&amp;gt; 00:04:07,614 and I asked the teacher: 85 00:04:07,614 --&amp;gt; 00:04:09,587 "What is it about you? 86 00:04:09,587 --&amp;gt; 00:04:11,655 Look at the paintings of the second grade. 87 00:04:11,655 --&amp;gt; 00:04:13,279 They are blotches of black and blue. 88 00:04:13,279 --&amp;gt; 00:04:15,447 Look at the paintings of the fourth grade. 89 00:04:15,447 --&amp;gt; 00:04:17,394 They are… you can't even understand. 90 00:04:17,394 --&amp;gt; 00:04:22,900 But the third grade, every painting is a Picasso. 91 00:04:22,900 --&amp;gt; 00:04:26,470 What is your secret? Let me learn with you." 92 00:04:26,470 --&amp;gt; 00:04:27,906 And the teacher says, 93 00:04:27,906 --&amp;gt; 00:04:31,864 "I just know when to take the painting away from them." 94 00:04:31,864 --&amp;gt; 00:04:34,697 So knowing when to give up 95 00:04:34,697 --&amp;gt; 00:04:39,030 is the most best skill we need to learn. 96 00:04:39,030 --&amp;gt; 00:04:40,818 Now the second thing is, 97 00:04:40,818 --&amp;gt; 00:04:44,488 this is Taiwan, this is the country of manufacturing. 98 00:04:44,488 --&amp;gt; 00:04:45,697 When I say B.O.M, 99 00:04:45,697 --&amp;gt; 00:04:46,891 what do people think? 100 00:04:46,891 --&amp;gt; 00:04:50,427 They think of bill of materials, right? 101 00:04:50,427 --&amp;gt; 00:04:51,947 But I want to give you a different definition of 102 00:04:51,947 --&amp;gt; 00:04:55,363 it after I tell you a few quick stories. 103 00:04:55,363 --&amp;gt; 00:04:58,001 Bill of materials is what is the content of things, 104 00:04:58,001 --&amp;gt; 00:04:59,503 what is in something. 105 00:04:59,503 --&amp;gt; 00:05:01,114 I want to introduce you to a few people 106 00:05:01,114 --&amp;gt; 00:05:03,030 who truly are my heroes. 107 00:05:03,030 --&amp;gt; 00:05:06,143 I mean these are the heroes of the new generation. 108 00:05:06,143 --&amp;gt; 00:05:08,697 This boy Sushant Patnaik. 109 00:05:08,697 --&amp;gt; 00:05:10,279 When he was about 15 years old, 110 00:05:10,279 --&amp;gt; 00:05:12,030 he went to the hospital and saw someone 111 00:05:12,030 --&amp;gt; 00:05:13,531 who was paraplegic 112 00:05:13,531 --&amp;gt; 00:05:16,280 and felt really about the person 113 00:05:16,280 --&amp;gt; 00:05:18,029 not being able to move. 114 00:05:18,029 --&amp;gt; 00:05:19,697 So he figured out what is common 115 00:05:19,697 --&amp;gt; 00:05:22,227 between him and the person who can not move 116 00:05:22,227 --&amp;gt; 00:05:23,427 is breath. 117 00:05:23,427 --&amp;gt; 00:05:25,362 So he created a wheel chair 118 00:05:25,362 --&amp;gt; 00:05:26,864 that moves through breath 119 00:05:26,864 --&amp;gt; 00:05:29,166 when he was aged 17. 120 00:05:29,166 --&amp;gt; 00:05:31,863 And since then he is all of 20 right now. 121 00:05:31,863 --&amp;gt; 00:05:34,471 He has already invented, you can make 122 00:05:34,471 --&amp;gt; 00:05:36,006 cell phone calls using breath, 123 00:05:36,006 --&amp;gt; 00:05:38,942 you can turn light on and off using breath. 124 00:05:38,942 --&amp;gt; 00:05:40,279 So he's dedicate to this idea. 125 00:05:40,279 --&amp;gt; 00:05:43,030 And this is Nam Do, 126 00:05:43,030 --&amp;gt; 00:05:45,113 who runs a company called Emotiv. 127 00:05:45,113 --&amp;gt; 00:05:48,486 And what this is, is that by thinking something, 128 00:05:48,486 --&amp;gt; 00:05:51,364 you can move objects on the screen. 129 00:05:51,364 --&amp;gt; 00:05:53,591 So what is the power of our thinking 130 00:05:53,591 --&amp;gt; 00:05:57,364 in making things happen in the physical world? 131 00:05:57,364 --&amp;gt; 00:06:01,614 Arunachalam, he is a 6th-grade-failed, 132 00:06:01,614 --&amp;gt; 00:06:03,234 and he was sitting at his house one day 133 00:06:03,234 --&amp;gt; 00:06:05,336 and he saw his wife was using rags 134 00:06:05,336 --&amp;gt; 00:06:07,072 when she had her periods. 135 00:06:07,072 --&amp;gt; 00:06:10,674 And he decided to invent the sanitary napkin 136 00:06:10,674 --&amp;gt; 00:06:12,810 that is affordable for women. 137 00:06:12,810 --&amp;gt; 00:06:15,779 So that over 90% of the women in India 138 00:06:15,779 --&amp;gt; 00:06:17,613 and around the world who can not afford 139 00:06:17,613 --&amp;gt; 00:06:21,319 to wear a sanitary napkin would be able to use this invention. 140 00:06:21,319 --&amp;gt; 00:06:25,155 And to do that, he had to sacrifice a lot of things, 141 00:06:25,155 --&amp;gt; 00:06:26,446 because people thought he was weird. 142 00:06:26,446 --&amp;gt; 00:06:30,030 First of all, a guy trying to do this was weird enough. 143 00:06:30,030 --&amp;gt; 00:06:33,164 So when he couldn't find anybody to experiment 144 00:06:33,164 --&amp;gt; 00:06:35,614 to find out if the sanitary napkin is working or not, 145 00:06:35,614 --&amp;gt; 00:06:37,233 he actually wore it. 146 00:06:37,233 --&amp;gt; 00:06:38,969 And he took pig's blood, 147 00:06:38,969 --&amp;gt; 00:06:40,740 and connect it to the sanitary napkin. 148 00:06:40,740 --&amp;gt; 00:06:42,197 He'd be riding bikes, he'd could be walking everywhere, 149 00:06:42,197 --&amp;gt; 00:06:46,810 pumping this, to test how this works. 150 00:06:46,810 --&amp;gt; 00:06:48,946 I mean it takes guts to do this 151 00:06:48,946 --&amp;gt; 00:06:51,114 for a man from a small town. 152 00:06:51,114 --&amp;gt; 00:06:54,030 Elora Hardy is building homes out of bamboos. 153 00:06:54,030 --&amp;gt; 00:06:57,188 Not just any home, luxury homes out of bamboo. 154 00:06:57,188 --&amp;gt; 00:06:59,823 Mansukhbai, he has created a refrigerator 155 00:06:59,823 --&amp;gt; 00:07:03,994 that runs through water that does not require electricity 156 00:07:03,994 --&amp;gt; 00:07:09,031 that keeps food cold for at least 2-3 days. 157 00:07:09,031 --&amp;gt; 00:07:10,447 And Maira Kalman, 158 00:07:10,447 --&amp;gt; 00:07:12,302 who is the illustrator with 'The New Yorker', 159 00:07:12,302 --&amp;gt; 00:07:14,306 who's a children's book artist. 160 00:07:14,306 --&amp;gt; 00:07:17,197 And Tod Machover who is the music composer, 161 00:07:17,197 --&amp;gt; 00:07:20,611 who's creating symphony of cities. 162 00:07:20,611 --&amp;gt; 00:07:23,982 He collects sounds of the cities and creates symphonies out of them. 163 00:07:23,982 --&amp;gt; 00:07:25,697 And the reason I'm talking about 164 00:07:25,697 --&amp;gt; 00:07:28,280 all of these people is that in my mind the B.O.M 165 00:07:28,280 --&amp;gt; 00:07:30,054 actually stands for 166 00:07:30,054 --&amp;gt; 00:07:32,323 Billionaires of Moments. 167 00:07:32,323 --&amp;gt; 00:07:34,364 And one of my favorite quotes is that: 168 00:07:34,364 --&amp;gt; 00:07:39,897 "Life ought not to be measured by the number of breaths we take, 169 00:07:39,897 --&amp;gt; 00:07:43,447 but by the number of moments that take our breath away." 170 00:07:43,447 --&amp;gt; 00:07:47,004 So each of these person that I've talked to you about 171 00:07:47,004 --&amp;gt; 00:07:51,530 is creating a world where there are many, many 172 00:07:51,530 --&amp;gt; 00:07:55,445 precious moments that are collected for the people around them. 173 00:07:55,445 --&amp;gt; 00:07:59,752 That's the billionaires that we all should aim to become. 174 00:07:59,752 --&amp;gt; 00:08:03,447 We should be greedy about collecting these moments. 175 00:08:03,447 --&amp;gt; 00:08:05,696 And finally, 176 00:08:05,696 --&amp;gt; 00:08:08,114 when we do this, when we do these crazy things, 177 00:08:08,114 --&amp;gt; 00:08:09,780 when we do these out-of-the-box things, 178 00:08:09,780 --&amp;gt; 00:08:12,529 when we do this nobody believes in, 179 00:08:12,529 --&amp;gt; 00:08:14,899 there are times you wonder 180 00:08:14,899 --&amp;gt; 00:08:17,197 "Why am I doing this?" 181 00:08:17,197 --&amp;gt; 00:08:18,636 You know there was a time 182 00:08:18,636 --&amp;gt; 00:08:20,237 when I used to love climbing mountains. 183 00:08:20,237 --&amp;gt; 00:08:21,530 So in the middle of the night 184 00:08:21,530 --&amp;gt; 00:08:23,697 you know you are up in some snow mountain, 185 00:08:23,697 --&amp;gt; 00:08:25,779 and it's cold as hell. 186 00:08:25,779 --&amp;gt; 00:08:27,365 And you are thinking of 187 00:08:27,365 --&amp;gt; 00:08:29,747 "What the heck am I doing here?" 188 00:08:29,747 --&amp;gt; 00:08:32,300 You know? And then you go down 189 00:08:32,300 --&amp;gt; 00:08:33,781 and then like an idiot next weekend 190 00:08:33,781 --&amp;gt; 00:08:35,696 again you're back up again. 191 00:08:35,696 --&amp;gt; 00:08:39,446 So what is this craziness that makes us all move? 192 00:08:39,446 --&amp;gt; 00:08:43,259 It is this word I want you to remember: one. 193 00:08:43,259 --&amp;gt; 00:08:46,863 Yi. Ek. Any language. 194 00:08:46,863 --&amp;gt; 00:08:48,279 one 195 00:08:48,279 --&amp;gt; 00:08:51,068 we should always think of one person 196 00:08:51,068 --&amp;gt; 00:08:52,269 or one incident 197 00:08:52,269 --&amp;gt; 00:08:54,572 something in our life 198 00:08:54,572 --&amp;gt; 00:08:58,676 that makes us go forward. 199 00:08:58,676 --&amp;gt; 00:09:01,445 And, to me, is this girl. 200 00:09:01,445 --&amp;gt; 00:09:04,582 I called her my flower girl. 201 00:09:04,582 --&amp;gt; 00:09:09,114 And I met her about 5 years ago. 202 00:09:09,114 --&amp;gt; 00:09:11,780 And she is in a home 203 00:09:11,780 --&amp;gt; 00:09:14,947 which rescues sex workers. 204 00:09:14,947 --&amp;gt; 00:09:17,196 And she was one of the girls that was rescued. 205 00:09:17,196 --&amp;gt; 00:09:19,696 she was about 6-years-old 206 00:09:19,696 --&amp;gt; 00:09:20,831 when was rescued. 207 00:09:20,831 --&amp;gt; 00:09:22,332 And she was brought home 208 00:09:22,332 --&amp;gt; 00:09:24,447 and she was taking care of. 209 00:09:24,447 --&amp;gt; 00:09:26,030 And then, 210 00:09:26,030 --&amp;gt; 00:09:29,947 um...you know she's mentally challenged. 211 00:09:29,947 --&amp;gt; 00:09:32,030 So they put her at the home. 212 00:09:32,030 --&amp;gt; 00:09:34,678 And they found out, two years later, 213 00:09:34,678 --&amp;gt; 00:09:38,015 that in that home she's been abuse again. 214 00:09:38,015 --&amp;gt; 00:09:40,114 So they brought her back to the home, 215 00:09:40,114 --&amp;gt; 00:09:42,697 and Sunitha Krishnan who runs this organization 216 00:09:42,697 --&amp;gt; 00:09:46,948 spoke in the conference just like this in India at TED. 217 00:09:46,948 --&amp;gt; 00:09:49,660 And she shared her story about 218 00:09:49,660 --&amp;gt; 00:09:52,697 how difficult it is to create a home 219 00:09:52,697 --&amp;gt; 00:09:55,067 for women like this who get rescued. 220 00:09:55,067 --&amp;gt; 00:09:58,101 Because no one wants them living in their neighborhood. 221 00:09:58,101 --&amp;gt; 00:10:01,364 And just like you 222 00:10:01,364 --&amp;gt; 00:10:02,617 there were people sitting in the audience. 223 00:10:02,617 --&amp;gt; 00:10:03,446 They got up. 224 00:10:03,446 --&amp;gt; 00:10:05,864 And we actually work with her for 6 months. 225 00:10:05,864 --&amp;gt; 00:10:08,946 And we got her enough money 226 00:10:08,946 --&amp;gt; 00:10:10,281 to build the home 227 00:10:10,281 --&amp;gt; 00:10:12,115 for all the women. 228 00:10:12,115 --&amp;gt; 00:10:14,151 So that 18 months from the time 229 00:10:14,151 --&amp;gt; 00:10:16,722 she stood and shared her story, 230 00:10:16,722 --&amp;gt; 00:10:20,558 there's a home where all these women were living. 231 00:10:20,558 --&amp;gt; 00:10:23,595 And to me, I felt that 232 00:10:23,595 --&amp;gt; 00:10:26,947 this girl, this face, 233 00:10:26,947 --&amp;gt; 00:10:29,167 is what haunted me. 234 00:10:29,167 --&amp;gt; 00:10:31,603 I felt I wanted to give her a home 235 00:10:31,603 --&amp;gt; 00:10:33,198 at least for one day 236 00:10:33,198 --&amp;gt; 00:10:35,279 where she was happy. 237 00:10:35,279 --&amp;gt; 00:10:36,614 And they built the home 238 00:10:36,614 --&amp;gt; 00:10:37,908 and pretty soon after that, 239 00:10:37,908 --&amp;gt; 00:10:39,142 she died. 240 00:10:39,142 --&amp;gt; 00:10:41,578 Because at age 9 or 10, 241 00:10:41,578 --&amp;gt; 00:10:44,614 by the time she was rescued for the second time, 242 00:10:44,614 --&amp;gt; 00:10:47,084 her body was ravaged with so much disease 243 00:10:47,084 --&amp;gt; 00:10:50,723 that she could not survive anymore. 244 00:10:50,723 --&amp;gt; 00:10:52,256 But to me, 245 00:10:52,256 --&amp;gt; 00:10:55,614 every time I think of the crazy things that we do, 246 00:10:55,614 --&amp;gt; 00:10:58,731 every time I think of all these 247 00:10:58,731 --&amp;gt; 00:11:01,365 billionaires of moments we are trying to create, 248 00:11:01,365 --&amp;gt; 00:11:03,834 every time we are sitting here biting our nails 249 00:11:03,834 --&amp;gt; 00:11:07,470 wondering if we are ever gonna make it through the year, 250 00:11:07,470 --&amp;gt; 00:11:09,973 and every time when I wonder, 251 00:11:09,973 --&amp;gt; 00:11:13,244 should I just go back and get a job, 252 00:11:13,244 --&amp;gt; 00:11:15,779 I just think of this face. 253 00:11:15,779 --&amp;gt; 00:11:20,197 And I think of the story with which I'm gonna end. 254 00:11:20,197 --&amp;gt; 00:11:25,197 And the story is of a little boy and starfish. 255 00:11:25,197 --&amp;gt; 00:11:26,823 And this boy goes to the beach, 256 00:11:26,823 --&amp;gt; 00:11:29,530 and there's millions of starfish out there. 257 00:11:29,530 --&amp;gt; 00:11:31,614 And this boy is taking each starfish 258 00:11:31,614 --&amp;gt; 00:11:33,613 and putting it back into the ocean. 259 00:11:33,613 --&amp;gt; 00:11:36,864 And then the waves come and wash a few more starfish 260 00:11:36,864 --&amp;gt; 00:11:38,614 and he keeps doing it. 261 00:11:38,614 --&amp;gt; 00:11:41,105 Finally an adult who is watching all this, 262 00:11:41,105 --&amp;gt; 00:11:43,614 you know, somebody smart like one of like us, 263 00:11:43,614 --&amp;gt; 00:11:45,642 goes to the child and says, 264 00:11:45,642 --&amp;gt; 00:11:47,377 "Why are you doing this? 265 00:11:47,377 --&amp;gt; 00:11:49,059 Why are you putting each because they are just 266 00:11:49,059 --&amp;gt; 00:11:50,978 gonna come right back again 267 00:11:50,978 --&amp;gt; 00:11:52,750 only few of them really make it. 268 00:11:52,750 --&amp;gt; 00:11:55,285 So why do you wanna spend all your day doing this?" 269 00:11:55,285 --&amp;gt; 00:11:56,086 He says, 270 00:11:56,086 --&amp;gt; 00:11:57,787 "Yes a lot of them may wash out, 271 00:11:57,787 --&amp;gt; 00:12:02,227 but for the one starfish that makes it, 272 00:12:02,227 --&amp;gt; 00:12:04,143 I made a difference." 273 00:12:04,143 --&amp;gt; 00:12:09,227 So, the world may or may not be available to you. 274 00:12:09,227 --&amp;gt; 00:12:11,602 But to one person, 275 00:12:11,602 --&amp;gt; 00:12:13,226 you may be the world. 276 00:12:13,226 --&amp;gt; 00:12:19,110 And let that person be your guiding light as 277 00:12:19,110 --&amp;gt; 00:12:22,947 you get to be billionaires of moments. 278 00:12:22,947 --&amp;gt; 00:12:26,415 Thank you. 279 00:12:26,415 --&amp;gt; 00:12:27,560 (Subtitled by Samantha Hu)
</field>
<field name="lang">
en-US
</field>

</doc>
<doc>
<field name="id">
3h-jSnGekIs
</field>
<field name="link">
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3h-jSnGekIs
</field>
<field name="tags">
Mixtec People (Ethnicity). Mexico. Lila Downs. Languages. Sierra. Mountains. Spanish. Musica. Oaxaca. Mixteco. ted talk. Mole. Textile. Cumbia. Mixtec. tedx. ted. performance. tedx talks. Idioma. English. CATAPULTAFEST. Comida. ted x. TEDxOaxacaCity. TEDx. Huipil. tedx talk. Anthropology. ted talks. Food
</field>
<field name="categories">
Music
</field>
<field name="description">
Lila Downs is the daughter of a Mixtec Indian woman, Anastasia Sanchez, who ran away from her village at 19 to sing in Mexico City cantinas and a Minnesota-born, Scottish-American professor, Allen Downs, who saw her singing and fell in love. Lila Downs was born in 1967 in the Oaxacan mountain town of Tlaxiaco, 7,000 feet up in the heavens. Her border-blurring, multicultural upbringing infused Downs with a firm world view in support of the disenfranchised working classes and an aesthetic vision that embraces cross-cultural pollinations.ESP: La potencia de su voz en inconfundible, puede explorar la cavernosa profundidad de la nostalgia ranchera, pero tambi\xe9n las agudas mieles de los cantos de fiesta. Lila ha creado un estilo \xfanico en el que se entreveran la m\xfasica tradicional oaxaque\xf1a con ritmos de todo M\xe9xico, as\xed como con estilos de todas partes del mundo, interpretando adem\xe1s canciones en lenguas como el mixteco y zapoteco.http://www.liladowns.com/mxIn the spirit of ideas worth spreading, TEDx is a program of local, self-organized events that bring people together to share a TED-like experience. At a TEDx event, TEDTalks video and live speakers combine to spark deep discussion and connection in a small group. These local, self-organized events are branded TEDx, where x = independently organized TED event. The TED Conference provides general guidance for the TEDx program, but individual TEDx events are self-organized.* (*Subject to certain rules and regulations).
</field>
<field name="title">
[Title of your video]: Lila Downs at TEDxOaxacaCity
</field>
<field name="text">
cuando yo era muy pequeña notaba que todos hablaban de una manera que me hacía muy incomoda porque manejaban muy bien el castellano o el español como decimos nosotros porque podían expresar sus opiniones y demás cosas que tienen que ver con la cultura. So I would like to say that I am about language and that is my issue in my life. And I switched to English because that is who I am and who I have been and who has taken me to be a musician. with no intention, originally. Mi primera intención era ser antropóloga porque yo vengo de una zona muy acidentada en las montañas de la Mixteca, un lugar que tiene una pobreza... pobreza de orgullo en parte por cosas muy dificiles que siguen viviendo va mucha gente a imigrar a Estados Unidos y yo veía estas historias desde que era muy chiquita, yo era parte de una de estas historias. Pero volviendo al tema del lenguaje, creo que lo que conseguí, porque traigo este hupil Triqui ahorita en parte porque hace mucho frío pero lo traje porque yo estudié este huipil, depués de haber seguido a the Greatful Dead un tiempo, after dropping out from life, from society and finding my own hippie family I went to the mountains of the place where I was born in Oaxaca and I studied this amazing textile, in part I was very attracted to it because the people in this community were the most discriminated in the State, this State has 16 different ethnics groups and languages And I wanted to learn more about this and I found that the textile is a historic document because it has symbols that date from prehispanic times to contemporary times. There is a symbol for the road, for the TV, for revolutionary times and I learned that this was women language an I learned that I wanted to part take. I dind´t consciously make that decision. Me decidí yo creo poco a poco porque la música me fue llevando a través del canto, de cantar, cantar, cantar, decir, pensar, escribir y como todos han dicho en esta noche, es cosa de hacer, de agarrar el machete o de agarrar la pala y empezar a escavar y eso es lo que he hecho con mi pluma, ahora con mi i pod y... ... y bueno, voy a hacer un sacrificio aquí... Y luego, he compuesto algún tema dedicado al lenguaje de la comida en México, estando lejos de México.. a ese lugar me ha llevado la música, el pensamiento, mi corazón... con esta canción que se llama: la ´Cumbia del mole´.
</field>
<field name="lang">
en-US
</field>

</doc>
<doc>
<field name="id">
x89AvFSdC3s
</field>
<field name="link">
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=x89AvFSdC3s
</field>
<field name="tags">
ted x. tedx. unicamp. tedx talk. portuguese. tedxunicamp. ted talks. brazil. tedxunicamp 2012. tedxunicamp2012. ted. tedx talks. ted talk. nics
</field>
<field name="categories">
Nonprofits &amp; Activism
</field>
<field name="description">
J\xf4natas Manzolli (NICS)Tema: Composi\xe7\xe3o Musical N\xf4madeCompositor e matem\xe1tico, atua em Arte e Tecnologia. Foi pioneiro no desenvolvimento de interfaces gestuais e trabalha com o conceito de auto-organiza\xe7\xe3o em sistemas evolutivos, rob\xf3ticos e espa\xe7os inteligentes. Produz obras mediadas por sistemas digitais e desenvolve ambientes computacionais para design sonoro e performance interativa. \xc9 Livre Docente do Departamento de M\xfasica e Coordenador do NICS, Unicamp, PhD em Composi\xe7\xe3o Musical pela Universidade de Nottingham, UK, com especializa\xe7\xe3o em Sonologia pelo Conservat\xf3rio Real de Haia, Holanda.Acknowledgments:Dancers:Aline BrazilCantelli CarolinaGabriel TolgyesiDaniela MoraisNathan RanhelDirector: Teresa RanieriInteractive System: Bruno PerosaSound Process: J\xf4natas ManzolliIn the spirit of ideas worth spreading, TEDx is a program of local, self-organized events that bring people together to share a TED-like experience. At a TEDx event, TEDTalks video and live speakers combine to spark deep discussion and connection in a small group. These local, self-organized events are branded TEDx, where x = independently organized TED event. The TED Conference provides general guidance for the TEDx program, but individual TEDx events are self-organized.* (*Subject to certain rules and regulations)
</field>
<field name="title">
Composi\xe7\xe3o musical n\xf4made: Jonatas Manzolli at TEDxUnicamp
</field>
<field name="text">
Good afternoon, my name is Jônatas. I am teacher, composer and mathematician. I would like to share with you a concept that pursues me for many years, since my PhD. which is: How to transfer methods for composing music using mathematical and computational algorithms to other media. that is not necessarily the (musical) score. As we saw here, the score. So if we search, it is possible to see that in Music History, starting upon the Gregorian chant, scores have had many shapes. Suddenly, in the 20th century, composers used representations of sound clouds, graphics, and also some composers used, not only the score, but also developed computer code to create music. So what is the point here? There is a query. It might be that the Beethoven's notepad that contained his ideas, was very effective to retain these ideas. It was based on a representation, the Cartesian one that you know. So the traditional score sheet is a representation of the Cartesian Plan. Isn't it? But in the end what really matters is what Manu (previous speaker) said: what matters is the music! The (Beethoven's) Eroica is its sound result! And therefore, as always I used to say to my students: The score is not the music. In any way! The score is a way of mediating music within an interpretive perspective. So there are issues that go beyond this lecture, or the focus of this lecture. They involve three aspects: the subject, the Art produced inside a cultural context, whatever it is, and the technology. I believe you don't think that technology is just computers, and in any way, isn't it? We have heard about the fire. We have heard about several things, but perhaps, one of the most important technologies that mankind developed was the writing, the transcription, the ability of representing. Perhaps what the researcher Marcelo Dascal calls Cognitive Technologies and these go beyond. What is important is that suddenly a writing technology provides means to us to create new sounds. What you are listening now is the Crab Canon. It was part of the Bach's Musical Offering. What is interesting here is that: there is something in this Canon that permeates our listening. It is related to the way it was written. Even if you are not reading this score in detail it is possible to see that there is a very interesting horizontal symmetry in it. That is is like a palindrome. If you look at the middle of the score, in its center of gravity. Its center, are you seeing that? All that is above and below is equal everything that is below and above. It's a such a perfect palindrome that one can play the score back and forth, and it will just sound exactly the same. But now there is an issue here: what makes it possible? It is, considering Bach's inventiveness, the representation, the medium. The symmetry that we see is there on the score. It is related to the way that the code was transcribed. The symmetry is on the score, in a certain way. Now what does happen when we enlarge this concept? The important is that the ways of representation are the medium for our ideas. This is very important to Art production and, especially, to composition. Actually, composers are seeking for medium to support their ideas. So, let us watch a work that we produced (to this talk). At the first moment they are playing with these interfaces, discovering it. They are using interfaces with sensors, the Wiimote, from the video-game. Sound parameters are related to their movement. Thus the movement itself, is the medium, the score. They are playing, they are discovering. Secondly, we asked them to perform a duo of movement. Now I would like to ask you to listen to this melody. Imagine, what is its generational process? Who did write that score, that music? What did generate this melodic profile? It has background and foreground sounds. Sounds coming and going. It has similarities, a degree of repetition. So the process that generated this was the movement of two dancers. In that case the medium, the representation, was related to their movement. There were also sensors placed on the roof to create relationship with their movements. So, what we are doing is the following: we are tracking their motion via software to map it to another representation, that is the sound, to produce a dialogue between them. It is important, they are performing free improvisation. But in this case they are working with movement and sound together. Finally, there is a notion I want to present here. It is perhaps a key issue here: the idea of sharing these representations may be such as a community whith several agents, where there are several factors such as the dancer's movement. Nevertheless, it is possible to share the constructiveness of the traditional score with movement. So, it becomes medium for musical achievements. I want to present you this possibility. Actually, the idea here is to create a textural discourse. It is not to create a discourse of melodies, or harmonies, but a discourse of view plans, points of view, plans for representing interactions. I am grateful to be able to show this result for you. (Participation of dancers: Aline Brazil) (Cantelli Carolina) (Gabriel Tolgyesi) (Daniela Morais) (Nathan Ranhel) They are holding the interfaces in their hands and they are working with their bodies. (Director: Teresa Ranieri) (Interactive System: Bruno Perosa) (Sound Process: Jônatas Manzolli) Thus, (musical) composition can migrate to the dancers' body. So it could also migrate to other representations. What is important here? I would like to emphasize that when we are listening to music, we are anticipating, we are looking forward to discover something. We are inquiring into every second of music that we are listening to. But music is not to be understood because it is an experience to be lived by each of us. Thus listening is a recreational process. I would like to thank very much Teresa (Ranieri) Bruno (Perosa), that is here, I saw him, and the dancers (Aline Brazil, Carolina Cantelli, Gabriel Tolgyesi, Daniela Morais, Nathan Ranhel) Finally, what is important to me is to leave with you the (idea) that mediation between technology and medium of representation provide conciliation with issues that are very fundamental for us as humans. That is the notion of sharing ideas. The idea of developing creative processes. And above all, we can dismiss the concept of the Romantic and over-powered Composer to be able to share some music that we have inside, in each of us. Thank you
</field>
<field name="lang">
en-US
</field>

</doc>
<doc>
<field name="id">
OsxNhD6DS-0
</field>
<field name="link">
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OsxNhD6DS-0
</field>
<field name="tags">
brazil. tedxunicamp 2012. portuguese. tedx talk. ted x. ted talk. unicamp. tedx. ted talks. tedxunicamp. nics. tedx talks. tedxunicamp2012. ted
</field>
<field name="categories">
Nonprofits &amp; Activism
</field>
<field name="description">
Jos\xe9 Wilson Magalh\xe3es Bassani (CEB)"Conector Uretral: dispositivo para diagn\xf3stico de obstru\xe7\xe3o da uretra"Graduado em Ci\xeancias da Computa\xe7\xe3o pela UNICAMP. Mestre e Doutor em Engenharia Biom\xe9dica e Prof. Titular do Departamento de Engenharia Biom\xe9dica da Faculdade de Engenharia El\xe9trica e de Computa\xe7\xe3o. Realizou p\xf3s-doutoramento na Universidade da California (Riverside, USA) e na Universidade de Loyola (Chicago, USA) onde foi tamb\xe9m Associate Professor do Departamento de Fisiologia. Atualmente \xe9 Diretor do Centro de Engenharia Biom\xe9dica (CEB) da UNICAMP.In the spirit of ideas worth spreading, TEDx is a program of local, self-organized events that bring people together to share a TED-like experience. At a TEDx event, TEDTalks video and live speakers combine to spark deep discussion and connection in a small group. These local, self-organized events are branded TEDx, where x = independently organized TED event. The TED Conference provides general guidance for the TEDx program, but individual TEDx events are self-organized.* (*Subject to certain rules and regulations)
</field>
<field name="title">
Conector Uretral: Jos\xe9 W. M. Bassani at TEDxUnicamp 2012
</field>
<field name="text">
good afternoon! I will talk about a new device that should benefit male individuals who may need some kind of clinical exam for diagnosis of urethral obstruction I am going to explain what it is about The 2010 census revealed that more than 9 million Brazilian men are over 60 years of age Of these, approximately 50% are prone to develop symptoms caused by a condition called benign prostatic hyperplasia which is a benign enlargement of the prostate; it is called benign because it is not due to cancer or another type of tumor very well this means that  4.5 million men are in this condition To better understand it, let us see the anatomy of the urinary system the urine is produced by the kidneys the urine flows via the ureters to the urinary bladder When the urine volume in the bladder reaches a certain level the micturition reflex is triggered As a result, the detrusor muscle in the bladder wall contracts and the urine is eliminated through the urethra The prostate is a gland located close to the bladder outlet encircling the urethra It is thus possible to refer to prostatic urethra and penile urethra As shown in this simplified cartoon when the detrusor muscle contracts in normal individuals the intravesical pressure (i.e., inside the bladder) rises. This increase in pressure drives the urinary flow In the benign prostatic hyperplasia the enlarged gland constricts the prostatic urethra, which causes the obstruction of the latter This is what underlies the obstruction of which I was talking In this case, the urinary flow is reduced and the detrusor muscle develops hyperthrophy which is an increase in its mass , and it can develop greater force that can overcome the greater resistance to the flow with stronger contraction of the detrusor muscle, the pressure generated in the bladder will be much greater The greater intravesical pressure may compromise the urine flow from the kidneys to the bladder and thus the renal function On the other hand, the hypertrophic growth may lead to gradual degeneration of the detrusor muscle of the bladder The development of urethral obstruction causes symptoms for instance, difficult and/ or painful micturition among others When the symptoms show the man seeks medical assistance and the physician requests, when the symptoms are severe, the urodynamic exam which is the conventional test In this exam a scary probe the so called vesical probe is introduced in the urethra to reach the interior of the bladder so that the vesical pressure can be measured This pressure is an important parameter for the decision regarding the need of prostate resection , which is the surgical reduction of the prostatic mass , that is, the prostate surgery Another equally scary probe is introduced for vesical filling , and thereafter the bladder content is voided by the patient so that the urinary flow can also be measured I confess that when I first saw the description of this procedure, I could not help thinking of myself or of the poor patient in the following situation: The patient connected to equipments bearing the urethral probe the vesical probe in the presence of the physician, the nurse , plus the Corinthians [famous Brazilian soccer team] fans, whom are not here today and, in this situation, the doctor asks him to please urinate normally This is a situation far from comfortable. We know that the hospital environment is less crowded and more controlled than this however, the exam is certainly invasive , uncomfortable , costly time-consuming, and is not devoid of problems For instance, there is serious risk of urinary infection There are two points worth stressing here. One is that 35% of the individuals who undergo this exam , the lucky ones who will not need the surgery still had to go through the exam procedure , so that it could show that their vesical pressure is not abnormally elevated In addition, I cannot imagine someone mentally sound who would undergo this exam in the absence of symptoms, as a routine test OK, and what could be done about it? To get together a multidisciplinary biomedical engineering team to find a solution for this problem This team includes institutes and centers of this university professionals with engineering background students and faculty from the fields of Medicine, Electrical Engineering and Computing Engineering This team came out with a very simple device which basically is a conical tube bearing in one of its extremities a pressure transducer The original idea was developed and came to be what we call urethral connector The conical extremity of the connector is introduced into the penile urethra of the patient He then urinates through the device, and at a certain point in time, the pressure is measured by the pressure transducer OK, to achieve this, the team developed the instrumentation , including the software and the interfaces, in short, the whole instrument that allows the necessary measurements With it, the urodynamic exam could become something like this: the tip of the connector is inserted into the penile urethra by the patient himself, if he will Then he urinates through the connector During the micturition the patient uses his gloved finger, to rapidly occlude the connector outlet once or twice, for a couple of seconds. This occlusion causes, as you can see, the pressure to rise for a period long enough to allow stabilization This stable value of pressure is the pressure in the system in the absence of flow during the short period in which the connector was occluded This can be considered as the static pressure which is the same throghout the whole system. Consequently this pressure value is equal to the vesical pressure. Thus, by using concepts of electrical circuits, fluid mechanics, prototyping, anatomy, physiology, computer programming and basic physics etc our team could develop instrumentation based on a relatively simple idea that allows measurement of the vesical pressure without the need of those scary probes This is an idea that we find worth spreading I would like to think that this idea would have social impact because it allows urodynamic populational studies It also makes it possible to perform the exam with preventive purposes , and to lower the cost of the exam for the diagnosis of urethral obstruction caused by prostate hyperplasia, which should make it accessible to a greater number of patients Thank you very much
</field>
<field name="lang">
en-US
</field>

</doc>
<doc>
<field name="id">
L-2XE0Wuock
</field>
<field name="link">
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=L-2XE0Wuock
</field>
<field name="tags">
tedx. disabled. courage. ted x. tedx talk. Slovak. handicapped. climbing. Entertainment. ted talks. limits. ted talk. tedx talks. Lifestyle. TEDxTalk. hiking. ted. Sports. slovakia
</field>
<field name="categories">
People &amp; Blogs
</field>
<field name="description">
He doesn't have an arm and a leg but what he does have is a big smile and a piece of mind we all dream of. He inspires other and the sky is his limit.About TEDx, x = independently organized eventIn the spirit of ideas worth spreading, TEDx is a program of local, self-organized events that bring people together to share a TED-like experience. At a TEDx event, TEDTalks video and live speakers combine to spark deep discussion and connection in a small group. These local, self-organized events are branded TEDx, where x = independently organized TED event. The TED Conference provides general guidance for the TEDx program, but individual TEDx events are self-organized.* (*Subject to certain rules and regulations)
</field>
<field name="title">
TEDxBratislava - Jasiek MELA -- Beyond the horizon of possibilities
</field>
<field name="text">
Hello. Hi. I&amp;nbsp;am very happy that today I&amp;nbsp;had an occasion to be here with you, to spend this day while watching and hearing these fascinating stories about people who, as I&amp;nbsp;think, are doing what they love to do. But let´s think about these people who haven’t arrived here at TED conference, about people who are not meeting with the others, about people who are just standing in their houses, they are not going out, they are not doing anything, about the people without hope. Why is it so, in such situation? Sky is the limit, everything is possible, it’s true, but it’s very easy to say it, to feel it, if you are looking in the&amp;nbsp;mirror and in this mirror you can see someone healthy, strong, handsome, young but if you see there someone disabled, the situation is completely different. Very long ago I&amp;nbsp;thought that every man received from the faith exactly that, what he should have in his life, I&amp;nbsp;though that bad ... not bad, because there is not bad experience, but I&amp;nbsp;thought that hard experience in life, they are some kind of of the punishment ... if we are bad people. This is mistake, but because of this mistake I&amp;nbsp;was unable to understand my life because I am so lucky guy but I lost very many things in my life. When I was 8, I lost my house which passed away in flames and then I was very young... but I thought we can’t lose anything more, because what else we can lose if we don’t have anything, even house. That wasn’t true, because the most important thing in life is just a&amp;nbsp;life- our life, life of our friends, of our family or of people who we love and suddenly I&amp;nbsp;had to understand it on my next hard experience 1 year later when I&amp;nbsp;lost my younger brother who drowned in a&amp;nbsp;lake. I&amp;nbsp;wanted to help him, but I&amp;nbsp;was just 9 and I&amp;nbsp;couldn’t swim, no one could help him... and you know after this day I&amp;nbsp;thought that this has to be just a&amp;nbsp;bad dream, only bad dream, but I&amp;nbsp;haven’t woke up since (until) today. Few years later when I&amp;nbsp;was 13 I&amp;nbsp;had an accident, electrical shock accident- I&amp;nbsp;had in my body 15 000 volts- after this accident I&amp;nbsp;spent 3 months in a&amp;nbsp;hospital, I&amp;nbsp;lost arm and leg. nd you know after this all experiences I&amp;nbsp;was still thinking: How is the rule of the world? Why I&amp;nbsp;am suffering so much? Why? Do I&amp;nbsp;deserve it? Or why? Since now I&amp;nbsp;don’t know an answer on this question, but I know that it’s not so important. I&amp;nbsp;know that even with this all experiences I&amp;nbsp;can tell you that I&amp;nbsp;am very lucky guy, because I&amp;nbsp;have so much luck to great people who I&amp;nbsp;met, I&amp;nbsp;have fantastic parents, who have always gave me a power to live and...all in all... in this time of this 3 months in a hospital I&amp;nbsp;was still loosing my hope. I&amp;nbsp;was thinking about my future or I&amp;nbsp;was unable to see this future in any colours I&amp;nbsp;thought that everything will be awful I&amp;nbsp;was 13 and I&amp;nbsp;didn’t start my life in a&amp;nbsp;full meaning of this world and I&amp;nbsp;thought that I&amp;nbsp;have to stop. I&amp;nbsp;won’t do anything more because what else can I do without arm and leg? How can I&amp;nbsp;find great studies and work like I want without arm and leg? How I&amp;nbsp;can travel? How I&amp;nbsp;can realize my dreams? How I can find a&amp;nbsp;woman who will look at me? I&amp;nbsp;thought everything will be completely awful, but after this accident my father told me the difference between disability and cripples. Disability is a&amp;nbsp;state of body. Someone who is blind, someone who is on a&amp;nbsp;wheelchair, someone without hand. He is disabled and it is so, it has to be so. But cripples is a&amp;nbsp;state of mind. You could have complete arms and legs, you could have everything inside in a&amp;nbsp;correct position and without dreams, without seeing inside your head, you are completely disabled. Now, loosing arm and leg it isn‘t a&amp;nbsp;problem, loosing a&amp;nbsp;head... this is a&amp;nbsp;disability. After accident I&amp;nbsp;understood that I&amp;nbsp;am disabled and I&amp;nbsp;have to just like it, but I&amp;nbsp;can’t agree with my cripples. I&amp;nbsp;won’t be a cripple. I want to live normally. After that I&amp;nbsp;met very many people who live in a&amp;nbsp;normal way, who showed me that the accident doesn’t have to be the end of life. Sometimes it is just a&amp;nbsp;start. I&amp;nbsp;remember a&amp;nbsp;woman who I&amp;nbsp;met in Krakow, in Poland. I&amp;nbsp;met a&amp;nbsp;woman without both hands. When I&amp;nbsp;spotted her, I&amp;nbsp;was thinking: How she could find the&amp;nbsp;sence of life. How she could live? How she could be happy? How she could smile... why? Why she should smile, because of what? ...without hands. Does she need always someone who is helping her with every simple thing? I&amp;nbsp;was thinking in this way. But I&amp;nbsp;saw a&amp;nbsp;happy woman, who was talking about her dreams, about her passions and we came to the restaurant, we have been talking about crazy things, and when a&amp;nbsp;kellner (waiter) came with&amp;nbsp;food and I&amp;nbsp;was completely stressed, because I&amp;nbsp;didn’t know what I have to do… you know we have food, but she doesn’t have hands. What should I do? Maybe I should feed her. For me it is not a problem, that could be quite romantic... I felt very strange. But she was so open-minded that I knew that when she will need my help she will just ask. But she didn’t ask, she didn’t need my help. Sitting at this table, she put off her boots... I&amp;nbsp;won’t show that... and she cought in the foot in the foot she cought the spoon and... what is the name... „videlec“ (polish expression for fork) (laugh) sorry... and in this way she just started to eat. For me, that was fantastic. I&amp;nbsp;know that it‘s not normal, it’s not elegant to look at with open (mounth), but for me that was phenomenal. In this day I&amp;nbsp;changed my changed my style of looking at the life, but for her that was just a&amp;nbsp;normal day... one of the days of her long life, but for other people that was something completely fantastic, completely great. You know, after accident I had to learn how to live, how to do normal things completely normal things, like slicing the bread, making something- making a tea was for me completely impossible. At the beginning I didn’t have prothesis, now I have cool leg prothesis, sometimes it’s imposible to see that something is wrong, but this is really great prothesis. After 8 years from accident I&amp;nbsp;could do almost everything but after the accident, you know, learning how to live, how to use one leg, one hand, that was not so easy. But that was only the element, that was quite easy, but the most difficult was to accept myself. To say that I&amp;nbsp;am OK. I&amp;nbsp;have 2 younger sisters and very often before school I&amp;nbsp;saw them near the mirror and the were saying: "Oh, mum, my nose is so big... I&amp;nbsp;am so so fat" and I&amp;nbsp;have a&amp;nbsp;question for everyone of you, but maybe especially to women. Have you ever had a&amp;nbsp;morning, when you woke up, stand near the mirror, look and thought: "Oh my god, I&amp;nbsp;am so unperfect." Sometimes yes. Imagine what you could feel if you are looking on this mirror and you are not thinking about the hair, about the nose, but in this mirror you can see the&amp;nbsp;man without hand and leg. This is really the&amp;nbsp;problem. But I&amp;nbsp;knew that this is only the beginning. I&amp;nbsp;knew that if I&amp;nbsp;want to live I&amp;nbsp;can do almost everything- if this woman without hands could live normally, I&amp;nbsp;can do it also. As I&amp;nbsp;told you, I&amp;nbsp;am very lucky guy. I&amp;nbsp;met very many fantastic people, and without this people I&amp;nbsp;couldn’t do crazy things like this all what you can see on this photographs. After accident I&amp;nbsp;met... not by coincidence, because I&amp;nbsp;don’t believe in coincidence, but I&amp;nbsp;met famous polish Explorer Marek Kaminski. He is man who was many times on North Pole, South Pole, on different deserts, many tabs completely insane man and when I&amp;nbsp;was in a&amp;nbsp;hospital, my mother, my parents were thinking what to do to give me a&amp;nbsp;hope- a&amp;nbsp;hope that I&amp;nbsp;can do normal things, that I&amp;nbsp;can do completely normally and they decided to invite Marek Kaminski to me, to the hospital. Marek of course agreed, but we haven’t an occasion to meet because I&amp;nbsp;had very many operations, but after that few months later we came to the office of Marek Kaminski and I&amp;nbsp;didn’t know anything, but in this time while this few months, Marek was thinking how to help me and he with his friends, they are a little bit crazy, and after maybe half an hour of talking Marek asked me: "Do I want to go with him to the North Pole?" ...you know… I like beer, but I wasn’t drinking at the age of 13 and... but I&amp;nbsp;felt like, like... that was completely crazy. But when I&amp;nbsp;understood it’s a&amp;nbsp;serious proposition, I&amp;nbsp;was thinking about that, thinking about possibilities and the barries and you know, it’s not so easy, because as I told you, if every simple things in my life was a&amp;nbsp;problem, if preparing a&amp;nbsp;tea is a&amp;nbsp;problem, what should I&amp;nbsp;do on the North Pole? It’s all completely crazy! It’s not a place for me. Maybe it’s a mistake of different addresses, different Jasiek Mela from Melbourne, but that wasn’t a mistake and at the beginning I thought that was completely impossible, but later I was thinking…but really…Why? Why not to try? I think that everyone of us should use every occasion to do something great in his life because great occasions if we let them pass away, they won’t in a time come back. So I&amp;nbsp;thought that, in fact, I&amp;nbsp;don’t have anything to lose. If we can’t do it, I will have a feeling that: OK, we didn’t manage it, but I’ve&amp;nbsp;just tried I&amp;nbsp;didn’t give up, because after this accident I learned that I can’t give up if I&amp;nbsp;want to live normally, I&amp;nbsp;have to fight and from this moment of our meeting to this moment from earlier photos, to expedition to the North Pole it took us 1,5 year. Not 1,5 year waiting, but 1,5 year trainings, preparations and what was the most difficult for me - meetings with other people. And that was so difficult because very many people told us that this idea is crazy, it is completely stupid. They told us... maybe it was a&amp;nbsp;little bit stupid, a little bit crazy, but this is the life. They told us that disabled man should be happy that he is alive after accident and not to do crazy things like travelling to the North Pole or places like that and at the beginning I&amp;nbsp;was still thinking about this, about this opinion I&amp;nbsp;was curious: Maybe it is true, maybe truly it is impossible but later I&amp;nbsp;thought that because of this people, because of that there... in our society we have so many this people who don’t believe in themself, who don’t believe in power of other people, we have to do it, We have to show everyone that I am not worse… that you know… it’s not the amount of arms and legs, this is about our strenght, about our power our power is inside here. We can have 3 or 4 hands and be more disabled than someone without legs but with wings ... if we only want and with this opinion after this 1,5 year of trainings we managed it. After that I&amp;nbsp;met very many people who needed this hope, who needed just hope to normal things, because we are trying to do crazy things like different expeditions to the South Pole, to Kilimandzaro, Elbrus, El Capitane not to show that I&amp;nbsp;can do it, I&amp;nbsp;am so cool because I&amp;nbsp;have been there and there and there, because I&amp;nbsp;am not an explorer. I&amp;nbsp;think that every expedition gives something inside, gives something ourselves, we are doing great things to show that the most important is the first step- just to go outside the house, because there are very many people who are just scared. After this very many fantastic experiences I&amp;nbsp;decided to manage to create my own foundation to help other people, because I&amp;nbsp;was helped. I&amp;nbsp;found very many people who helped me, but I&amp;nbsp;know that there are in our society, in your society, there are a&amp;nbsp;lot of people who don’t have this luck, who can’t say that they are very lucky, who haven’t met Marek Kaminski or different fantastic people and because of that we are trying to help them to do crazy things. I remember when once we’ve been organizing a small trip with blind people- a small climbing trip- and I&amp;nbsp;always had a fear of heights and when I&amp;nbsp;saw my friend Simon, who is completely blind, who was something about 4 or5 metres above the earth,I&amp;nbsp;just started yelling: "Simon you are so high! Aren’t you scared? that... you know you are 5 metres high." and he told me: "Jasiek stay cool. I&amp;nbsp;am blind, for me it’s not a&amp;nbsp;difference." So he always tells me that blind people have better situation because they just don’t see the barriers. (laught) Everything is only a&amp;nbsp;matter of perspective. If you want to see the bad things in life, you can see them. Of course, because they are part of our life, but good things also. As I&amp;nbsp;say an old lithuanian proverb: Every puddle, even the smallest one, reflects the sky. And it depends on us what we want to see. I&amp;nbsp;wish everyone of you the day full of puddles. And I&amp;nbsp;think the best puddles are this with plenty of gasoline, because they have not only the sky but they also...you can see the rainbow inside, then it’s nothing better than trying to see the colours in your life and I&amp;nbsp;wish you to alway have the head on the good place and then sky is the limit. Thank you.
</field>
<field name="lang">
en-US
</field>

</doc>
</add>
